跨越边境：时间迷宫
Ma cross Frontier: Labyrinth of Time
人类开始穿越恒星的旅程已经有半个多世纪了。
It's been over half a century since humanity began its journey across the stars.
在这段时间里，我们接触了许多外星种族，包括一些
During that time, we have come into contact with many alien races, including some
失落已久的星际文明的后裔，被称为亲文化。
descendants of the long lost interstellar civilization known as the Pro to culture.
为此，无论是在悲伤中还是在欢乐中，都流下了许多眼泪。
Many tears have been shed because of this, both in grief and in joy.
大家好！你们都玩得很开心吗？！
Hey everybody! You all having a good time?!
很抱歉这么说，但……下一首歌将是最后一首。
I'm sorry to say this, but... this next song will be the last one.
-啊！我们想要更多！-哦！我们想要更多！
- Aw! We want more! - Aw! We want more!
这首歌是献给我所珍爱的人的。
This song is for those I hold dear.
我希望你喜欢它。
I hope you like it.
毫无疑问，这些感觉都在我心里
Without a doubt these feelings are within me
无法控制，它们溢出
Unable to be contained, they overflow
当我想起你，我的胸怀就变成了宇宙，
When I think of you, my bosom becomes the universe,
紧握着星星
holding the stars close
我们的日子有限
Our days are limited
我们的日子是有限的，从那“致命的一天”开始已经有一段时间了。
Our days are limited It's been some time since that' fateful day.
我们的日子有限
Our days are limited
我决定用他们来爱你
I've decided to spend them loving you
我决定让他们爱你来结束那场悲惨的战争，
I've decided to spend them loving you To put an end to that tragic war,
我决定用他们来爱你
I've decided to spend them loving you
我决定用他们对你的爱来消磨谢丽尔用一首感动银河系的歌曲烧毁了她生命中剩下的一切。
I've decided to spend them loving you Sheryl burned what was left of her life with a song that moved the galaxy.
谢丽尔用一首感动银河系的歌曲烧毁了她生命中留下的一切。
Sheryl burned what was left of her life with a song that moved the galaxy.
我开始发现谢丽尔用一首感动银河系的歌曲燃烧了她生命中剩余的力量。
I'm starting to find the strength Sheryl burned what was left of her life with a song that moved the galaxy.
我开始找到力量了
I'm starting to find the strength
我开始找到力量直到今天，她仍然在睡觉。
I'm starting to find the strength To this day, she still sleeps.
我开始找到力量了
I'm starting to find the strength
说我爱你
to say I love you
这条路很长
It's a long road
由远处的灯光指引
Guided by the light shining in the distance
让我们永远再见面
Let us always meet again
兰卡？
Ranka?
…现在可以见面了
...able to meet now
这种感觉越来越深，
This feeling that grows ever deep,
这种感觉越来越深，嗯？！折叠波浪？！
This feeling that grows ever deep, Huh?! Fold Waves?!
呵呵？！折叠波浪？！
Huh?! Fold Waves?!
我发誓要坚持啊？！折叠波浪？！
I vow to keep Huh?! Fold Waves?!
我发誓要坚持
I vow to keep
我发誓要坚持-嘘！-嘘！
I vow to keep - Shush! - Shush!
我发誓要坚持
I vow to keep
愿它永不动摇
May it never waver
在寒风中
amidst the freezing wind
银河遗产局已经批准我们进行调查。
The Galactic Heritage Bureau has given clearance for us to investigate.
谢谢大家一直帮忙。
Thanks for always helping out, everyone.
检查丢失的技术也是超级维度巡演护送人员的工作。
Checking out lost technology is also the job of Super Dimensional Tour escorts.
此外，我们还可以去听你的音乐会。
Plus we get to go to your concerts.
不过，这个地方真是太棒了。
This place is really amazing though.
灵魂之井是亲文化后裔留下的庙宇。
The Well of Souls is a temple left behind by the descendants of the Pro to culture.
灵魂之井。。。
The Well of Souls...
一个与神交流的地方。
A place to commune with the gods.
传说它也被用来和死者交谈。
Legend says it was used to converse with the dead as well.
请快点，Ranka。
Please make this quick, Ranka.
你还有新歌歌词要完成。
You still have new song lyrics to finish.
明天我们将前往您的下一个旅游站。
And we leave for your next tour stop tomorrow.
对不起，让你担心。。。
Sorry for worrying you...
但我觉得这次我可能会联系到他。
But I feel that I might reach him this time.
干得好。太烧和金枪鱼面包，你的最爱。
Here you go. Taiyaki and tuna buns, your favorites.
这个设置每次看起来都像一个墓地。
This setup looks like a grave site every time.
嘿别那么说。
Hey! Don't say that.
这是正确的。阿尔托答应他会活着回来，所以就在那里。
That's right. Alto promised he'd come back alive, so there.
那是什么？
What was that?
折叠波浪！
Fold Waves!
正如我所想。它必须已重新激活以响应
Just as I thought. It must have reactivated in response to
昨晚音乐会上兰卡的声音。
Ranka's voice during last night's concert.
它在呼唤我。。。
It's calling me...
嗯？
Huh?
是阿尔托打来的！
It's Alto who's calling!
等待太危险了！
Wait! It's too dangerous!
这就是神秘的时间迷宫，
This is the mysterious Labyrinth of Time,
在那里，隐藏的记忆被唤醒
where hidden memories are awakened
隐藏的记忆唤醒了Ranka！
where hidden memories are awakened Ranka!
在那里，隐藏的记忆被唤醒
Where hidden memories are awakened
我为什么在这里？为什么是我？
Why am I here? Why me?
空洞的回答在我周围舞动
Empty answers dance all around me
即使只是一场梦，我也不在乎
Even if it's just a dream, I don't care
如果这意味着我可以改变过去，
If it means I can change the past,
我自己也会变成魔鬼
I'd become the Devil himself
兰卡！
Ranka!
我还记得那天
I still remember the day
你和我第一次见面
you and I first met
你和我第一次见面-嗯？-啊哈？
you and I first met - Huh'? - Aha'?
-啊？-阿尔托？
- Huh? - Alto?
那天的风有点小。真的是他吗？
The wind fell' kind of gentle that day. Is it really him?
那天的风感觉有点温和。
The wind felt kind of gentle that day.
那天的风有点小。不，这只是她的回忆。
The wind fell' kind of gentle that day. No, it's just her projected memories.
那天的风感觉有点温和。
The wind felt kind of gentle that day.
那天的风有点小。我从Ranka的大脑中得到了强有力的数据，
The wind fell' kind of gentle that day. I'm getting strong readings from both Ranka's brain,
我从Ranka的大脑中得到了强有力的数据，
I'm getting strong readings from both Ranka's brain,
（我有一种感觉……）我从Ranka的大脑中得到了很强的读数，
(I had a feeling...) I'm getting strong readings from both Ranka's brain,
（我有一种感觉……）
(I had a feeling...)
（我有一种感觉……）和她腹部的折叠细菌。
(I had a feeling...) and the Fold Bacteria in her abdomen.
还有她腹部的折叠细菌。
And the Fold Bacteria in her abdomen.
你太熟悉了；虽然我们只是刚刚见面，她的腹部有折叠细菌。
You fell' so familiar; though we only just met and the Fold Bacteria in her abdomen.
你觉得很熟悉，虽然我们只是刚刚见面
You felt so familiar, though we only just met
我有一种有趣的感觉
And I had a funny feeling that
也许你对我也有同样的感觉
maybe you felt the same way about me
从那天起，每天都很有趣
From that day on, every day was so much fun
如此悲伤
and so sad
只是有点孤独
And just a little bit lonely
我被这些感觉淹没了
I was overwhelmed by all those feelings
一想到你的名字我就不知所措
I was overwhelmed at the thought of your name
025-8和S04
025-8 and S04
你能听到我的声音吗？
Can you hear this voice of mine?
你能听到我的声音吗？你好，Ranka？
Can you hear this voice of mine? Hello, Ranka?
你好，Ranka？
Hello, Ranka?
我想让你给我看更多你好，Ranka？
I want you to show me more Hello, Ranka?
我想让你给我看更多
I want you to show me more
我想让你给我看更多什么？已经很晚了。
I want you to show me more What is it? It's pretty late.
这是怎么一回事？已经很晚了。
What is it? It's pretty late.
关于各种各样的明星这是什么？已经很晚了。
About all sorts of stars What is it? It's pretty late.
关于各种各样的明星
About all sorts of stars
关于各种各样的你
About all sorts of you
关于各种各样的你哦，所以你睡不着。
About all sorts of you Oh, so you can't sleep.
025-8和S04
025-8 and S04
025-8和S04那么，你能看到东方的天空吗？
025-8 and S04 Well then, can you see towards the eastern sky?
那么，你能看到东方的天空吗？
Well then, can you see towards the eastern sky?
你听到我的声音了吗？那么，你能看到东方的天空吗？
ls my voice reaching you? Well then, can you see towards the eastern sky?
你听到我的声音了吗？
Is my voice reaching you?
你听到我的声音了吗？没错，把灯关掉。
Is my voice reaching you? That's right, turn off the lights.
没错，把灯关掉。
That's right, turn off the lights.
我想让你告诉我更多。没错，把灯关掉。
I want you to tell me more That's right, turn off the lights.
我想让你告诉我更多
I want you to tell me more
关于各种各样的明星
About all sorts of stars
关于各种歌曲
About all sorts of songs
谢丽尔！
Sheryl!
拜托，阿尔托！回应
Please, Alto! Respond!
请快点回来。。。
Please, hurry back...
…为了谢丽尔！
...for Sheryl!
你需要叫醒谢丽尔！
You need to wake Sheryl!
我们走了不同的路，但做了同样的梦
We traveled separate paths, but dreamed the same dream
这就是为什么我并不孤单
That's why I wasn't alone
自从我失去了你，我感到你无处不在
Since I lost you, I feel your presence everywhere
你的形象，你头发的气味
The image of you, the scent of your hair
从那天起，每一天都是如此美好
From that day on, every day was so beautiful
太令人兴奋了
and so exciting
只是有点孤独
And just a little bit lonely
因为只有当我和你在一起的时候
Because only when I'm with you
星星会发光吗，
do the stars shine bright,
星星会发光吗？哇…嘿，大家都在看。
do the stars shine bright', Whoa... Hey, everyone's watching.
哇…嘿，大家都在看。
Whoa... Hey, everyone's watching.
大海变深了，哇…嘿，大家都在看。
The seas go deep, Whoa... Hey, everyone's watching.
天空高耸入云
And the skies reach high
O21-5和FO9
O21 -5 and FO9
你能听到我的声音吗？
Can you hear this voice of mine?
我想让你给我看更多
I want you to show me more
关于各种各样的明星
About all sorts of stars
关于各种各样的你
About all sorts of you
O21-5和FO9
O21 -5 and FO9
你听到我的声音了吗？
Is my voice reaching you?
我想让你告诉我更多
I want you to tell me more
关于各种各样的明星
About all sorts of stars
关于各种歌曲
About all sorts of songs
你现在觉得我怎么样？
What do you think of me now?
我变得更强了吗？
Have I become a stronger person?
我要你温柔地告诉我
I want you to tell me gently
当我是。。。
When I was...
爱上上帝。。。
in love with God...
O21-5和FO9
O21 -5 and FO9
我从没想过。。。
I never expected...
我从没想过…Sheryl？中音？！
I never expected... Sheryl? Alto?!
O21-5和FO9
O21 -5 and FO9
你听到我的声音了吗？
Is my voice reaching you?
-O21-5和FO9-FO9
-O21-5 and FO9 -FO9
-你听到我的声音了吗-FO9公司
-Is my voice reaching you? -FO9
我想让你告诉我更多
I want you to tell me more
关于各种各样的明星
About all sorts of stars
关于各种各样的明星如此美丽。。。
About all sorts of stars So pretty...
关于各种各样的你
About all sorts of you
关于各种各样的你，真是一首优美的歌。
About all sorts of you Such a beautiful song.
关于各种各样的你
About all sorts of you
关于各种各样的你她联系到他了吗？
About all sorts of you Did she reach him?
关于各种各样的你
About all sorts of you
关于各种各样的你，我都说不出来。
About all sorts of you I can't tell.
关于各种各样的你
About all sorts of you
-当我…025-8和04美元
-When I was... 025-8 and $04
-当/曾经是---O25-8和S04，但废墟中的折叠波仍在增强。
-When / was--- -O25-8 and S04 But the Fold Waves from the ruins are still getting stronger.
但废墟上的折叠波仍在增强。
But the Fold Waves from the ruins are still getting stronger.
你听到我的声音了吗？但废墟上的折叠波仍在增强。
ls my voice reaching you? But the Fold Waves from the ruins are still getting stronger.
你听到我的声音了吗？
Is my voice reaching you?
-爱上帝…-我想让你告诉我更多
-In love with God... -I want you to tell me more
关于各种各样的明星
About all sorts of stars
025-8美元和04 1025-8美元以及04美元）
025-8 and $04 1025-8 and $04)
你听到我的声音了吗？
Is my voice reaching you?
025-8美元和04 1025-8美元以及04美元）
025-8 and $04 1025-8 and $04)
我想让你告诉我更多
I want you to tell me more
025-8美元和04-04美元
025-8 and $04 -$04
-你听到我的声音了吗-$04
-ls my voice reaching you? -$04
我想保持这种感觉
I want to hold on to this feeling
我想保持这种感觉Alto？
I want to hold on to this feeling Alto?
我想保持这种感觉
I want to hold on to this feeling
我现在和你在一起
That I'm with you right now
025-8美元和04-04美元
025-8 and $04 -$04
-你听到我的声音了吗-联系您
-Is my voice reaching you? -Reaching you
我想保持这种感觉
I want to hold on to this feeling
我现在和你在一起Alto！
That I'm with you right now Alto!
我现在和你在一起
That I'm with you right now
-我现在和你在一起-（我现在跟你在一起）
-That I'm with you right now -(That I'm with you right now)
这是放大的折叠波传输！
It's an amplified Fold Wave transmission!
那是…他吗？
Is that... him?
在光的尽头。。。
At the end of the light...
这次我不会失去你。
I'm not losing you this time.
明亮的眼睛，陷入黑暗
Shining eyes, fall into the dark side
我不能再回去了
I can't go back again
破败之路
THE PATH OF RUIN
RUIN Sv-303备用启动路径。
THE PATH OF RUIN Sv-303 Standby to launch.
Sv-303待命启动。
Sv-303 Standby to launch.
这款Sv-303 Standby即将推出，这是一个精彩纷呈的世界。
A world played out through this Sv-303 Standby to launch.
一个世界经历了这一切
A world played out through this
一个世界通过本指南单元全部连接。
A world played out through this Guide units all connected.
一个世界经历了这一切
A world played out through this
一个世界通过这个空间压缩推力放大系统发挥了名义上的作用。
A world played out through this Spatial compression thrust amplification system nominal.
空间压缩推力放大系统标称值。
Spatial compression thrust amplification system nominal.
月光引导旋律空间压缩推力放大系统名义上。
Moonlight guided melody Spatial compression thrust amplification system nominal.
Moonl/jghz引导旋律
Moonl/jghz' guided melody
moonl/jghz“引导旋律0F V反应/子弹”集已完成
moonl/jghz' guided melody 0F V react/on bullet' set completed
0F V反作用/子弹设置完成
0F V react/on bullet' set completed
等待0F V反应/子弹设置完成
Wait to see 0F V react/on bullet' set completed
0F V反作用/子弹设置完成
0F V react/on bullet' set completed
OU/E TL Y 0F V react/on bullet“设置完成
whatis going on OU/E TL Y 0F V react/on bullet' set completed
OU/E TL Y发生了什么
whatis going on OU/E TL Y
OU/E TL Y多维折叠石英系统正在进行什么。
whatis going on OU/E TL Y Multidimensional Fold Quartz System synchronizing smooth/y.
多维F0/d石英系统同步平稳/y。
Multidimensional F0/d Quartz System synchronizing smooth/y.
DES THUG T/ON的调子是…多维F0/d石英系统平滑同步/y。
THE TUNE OF DES THUG T/ON IS... Multidimensional F0/d Quartz System synchronizing smooth/y.
$0 don'z'loo/r回来
$0 don 'z' loo/r back
埋伏等待革命的机会
Lying in wait for a chance at revolution
走进你，
Into you,
我们还没有办法
there is no way our NOT YET
等待时间
Wait for the time
唤醒安静/y，安静/y
of awakening quiet/y, quiet/y
必须准备好摇滚
Gotta be ready to rock
也许…你能，只有你能
Maybe... On/y you can, only you can
摇晃我
rock me
我知道你可以，我知道你能
I know you can, I know you can
/知道你可以，/知道你可以空间扭曲率增加。接近维度断层。
/ know you can, / know you can Space distortion rate increasing. Approaching Dimensional Fault.
空间失真率增加。接近维度断层。
Space distortion rate increasing. Approaching Dimensional Fault.
只有你可以，只有你可以空间扭曲率增加。接近维度断层。
Only you can, only you can Space distortion rate increasing. Approaching Dimensional Fault.
只有你能，只有你能
Only you can, only you can
摇晃我
rock me
警报器系统在操作参数范围内运行。
rock me Siren System operating within operational parameters.
Siren System operating within operational parameters.
7'0黑暗，至黑暗，警报器系统在操作参数范围内运行。
7'0 the darkness, to the darkness Siren System operating within operational parameters.
去摇滚吧，准备摇滚吧！好的现在，你的声音将打开通往新时代的大门，
Heady to rock, get ready to rock! Good. Now, thy voice shall open the gates to a new era,
好的现在，你的声音将打开通往新时代的大门，
Good. Now, thy voice shall open the gates to a new era,
倒计时到毁灭，是的！好的现在，你的声音将打开通往新时代的大门，
Countdown to ruin, YES! Good. Now, thy voice shall open the gates to a new era,
倒计时到毁灭，是的！
Countdown to ruin, YES!
倒计时到毁灭，是的！0'伟大的黑暗歌手。
Countdown to ruin, YES! 0' great Singer of the Dark.
去摇滚吧，准备摇滚吧！
Heady to rock, get ready to rock!
立即释放它
Unleash it now
准备好摇滚了
Gonna be ready to rock
进入你的内心
Into you
准备好摇滚了
Gonna be ready to rock
准备好了，准备好了！
Gonna be ready to, be ready to rock!
准备好了，准备好了！Macross Delta:ZETTAI L|VE！！！！！！
Gonna be ready to, be ready to rock! Macross Delta: ZETTAI L|VE!!!!!!
Macross Delta:ZETTAI L|VE！！！！！！
Macross Delta: ZETTAI L|VE!!!!!!
在过去的五十年里，温德米尔
For the past five decades, Windermere has been in
与地球人类不断发生激烈冲突。
constant bitter conflict with the humans of Earth.
对我们来说，
To us,
收回我们天空的自由是一场圣战。
it was a holy war to reclaim the freedom of our skies.
但即便如此，太多的翅膀和
But even so, too many wings and
失去了太多宝贵的生命。
too many precious lives have been lost.
让我们祈祷死者的灵魂
Let us pray that the souls of the departed
被风带到风之泉，让他们可以安息。
be borne by the wind to the Fountain of Wind so that they may rest in peace.
我们目前正在与联合国政府谈判一项和平条约。
We are current/y negotiating a peace treaty with the U.N. Government.
如果我尝试，我会飞。如果我尝试，我会飞。如果我尝试，我会飞。
If I try, I can fly. If I try, I can fly. If I try, I can fly.
-如果我尝试-Fre Fre！
- If I try— - Fre-Fre!
来吧，放松点。
Come on, loosen up.
Freyja，紧张到极点。
Freyja, tense to the max.
这是她逃跑后第一次回来
Well, this is her first time back since running away
来自她的村庄，加上她的国王举办了一场音乐会来庆祝停战。
from her village, plus it's a concert held by her king to celebrate the truce.
团结起来，否则就被甩在后面！
Get it together or be left behind!
好吧！
Alrighty!
献给团结在神圣羽毛下的风之子，
To the Children of the Wind united under the sacred feather,
我发誓要让和平之风席卷整个银河系。
I vow to make the winds of peace sweep throughout the galaxy.
以大风的名义！
In the name of the Great Wind!
向上爆炸！
Up ward Bomb Burst!
准备好迎接挑战了吗，红骑士？
Up for the challenge, Crimson Knight?
嘿，你这个无聊的白痴！
Heh, you dull-winded oaf!
去
Go!
什么
What?!
去
Go!
费用/单位：g00d/
Fee/in ' g00d./
哇！他在跳lmme/mann舞！
Whoa! He's do/'n' the lmme/mann dance!
海亚特，回到队形！
Hayate, get back in formation!
放松点，幻影，只要我们能搞定结局，演出就会很好-
Relax Mirage, the show will be fine as long as we nail the finale-
“爸爸/妈妈）你！-什么
' Da/nf) you! - What?!
你竟敢在陛下面前行动？！
You dare act out in the presence of His Majesty?!
这只是一点服务！
It's just a bit' 0f service!
您的服务不需要“1”/
Your service isn '1' needed./
还是个男孩。
Still just a boy.
-深红骑士'！回来！-抓住他，博格爵士！
- Crimson Knight'! Come back! - Get him, Sir Bogue!
啊…深红骑士有一些动作。
Ah... Crimson Knight's got some moves.
你那家伙的舞也跳得很好。
Your guy's dance isn '1' baa' either.
再见，红骑士！
See ya later, Crimson Knight'!
他/什么/
He y./ What the.../
音乐就是爱！
Music is Love!
音乐是希望！
Music is Hope!
音乐就是生活！
Music is Life!
音乐是神秘的！
Music is Mystery!
音乐就是能量！
Music is Energy!
听女神的歌！
Listen to the songs of goddesses!
超级维纳斯，沃尔基尔！
Super Dimension Venus, Walkiire!
/在游荡的冰川上
/n the wandering glacier
隐藏的秘密
a secret lies hidden
由于一次奇怪的意外
By a freak accident
发生了一次邂逅。所以限制
an encounter happened. So restricting
从混乱的深处涌上来
Welling up from the depths of chaos
深冻结显示了它的708个面
the deep freeze shows its 708 facets
L/ps所以哈！
L/ps so ha!
在我看来
That they seem to me/z'
Comp/ere熔解，i2'形式
Comp/ere meltdown, i2' forms
我不知道。只是重复
I don '2' know. Just repeating
这种冲动，
this urge,
让我出去。。。
letting i2' out...
纯洁的雪花触摸着我的手，因为它们相互吸引
Pure fa///ng snow touches my hand as they attract each other
我的性欲被唤醒了，头晕目眩
My fee//ngs become aroused, so dizzy
没有多余的生命，你和我，到了极限
N0 spare lives, you and me, to the limit
请接受它，
Please accept it,
这个吻，现在
this kiss, r/jghz' now
看，白银世界又回来了
See, the silver world returns
微弱的沉默声
The sound of silence that g/immered faintly
释放所有压抑的情绪，
Unleash all the pent-up emotions,
_美元/英尺_美元/英尺
_$/'flg _$/'flg
fi/flg（飞行/飞行）
fi/flg
我爱上了这个无限的星系
I fel/ in love, in this infinite galaxy
这些从我身上流露出来的感觉是如此的脱节
These feelings spilling out of me are so disjointed
他们没有恶意，所以他们相互重叠
They are inst/not without malice, so they overlap
暂时不要从我这里拿走它们
Don't take them from me just yet
纯洁的雪花触摸着我的手，因为它们相互吸引
Pure fa///ng snow touches my hand as they attract each other
我的性欲被唤醒了，头晕目眩
My fee//ngs become aroused, so dizzy
没有多余的生命，你和我，到了极限
N0 spare lives, you and me, to the limit
请接受它，
Please accept it,
这个吻，现在
this kiss, r/jghz' now
-沃尔基尔！-沃尔基尔！
- Walkiire! - Walkiire!
-弗雷亚！“苹果女孩！
- Freyja! " Apple Girl!
谢谢大家！
Thank you everybody!
Freyja的符文太亮了！
Freyja's rune is so bright!
多么耀眼的风啊，对符文来说是如此的惬意。
What a dazzling wind, so pleasant to the rune.
我希望Roid和Keith
I wish both Roid and Keith
我们是来感受这风的。
were here to feel this wind.
唷…嗯？
Whew... Huh?
弗雷亚？
Freyja?
这些房子很漂亮。
These houses are delightful.
他们真可爱！
They're so cute!
如此宁静。太激动了。
So serene. So excited.
是 啊真的很好，弗雷娅。。。
Yeah. It's really nice, Freyja...
嘿，怎么了？
Hey, what's wrong?
弗雷娅跑掉了，保释了她的订婚。
Freyja ran off, bailed on her engagement.
丽丽！
Rei-Rei!
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
市长先生！
Mister Mayor!
我真的真的…真的很抱歉！
I'm really, really... I'm so totally sorry!
看到你没事，我很欣慰，弗雷娅。
It's a relief to see you're okay, Freyja.
嗯？
Huh?
谢谢你照顾Freyja。
Thank you for taking care of Freyja.
我代表Ravengrass村的人，鞠躬我的符文。
On behalf of the people of Ravengrass Village, I bow my rune.
市长先生。
Mister Mayor.
不，是Freyja的声音
No, it was Freyja's voice
弥补了温德米尔和我们之间的差距。
that bridged the gap between Windermere and ourselves.
-弗雷亚！-弗雷亚！
- Freyja! - Freyja!
欢迎回来！
Welcome back!
-已经很久了。-符文·皮卡！
- It's been so long. - Rune Pika!
好了，伙计们，轮到你们了。
Alright guys, wait your turn.
M-Muah！干得好！
M-Muah! Here you go!
Gori Gori可爱！
Gori-Gori cute!
十连胜！
Ten win streak!
嘿，又弱又弱。
Heh, weak and feeble.
我是一个没有怜悯心的女人。
I'm a woman without mercy.
你曾与超级维度灰姑娘Ranka Lee合作过？！
You've performed with Ranka Lee, the Super Dimensional Cinderella?!
啊，是的。我曾经是个独唱偶像，所以。。。
Ah, yes. I used to be a solo idol, so...
我不会说你和她一起“表演”。
I wouldn't say you "performed with" her.
那是一个综艺节目，她在那里看了你的视频
It was a variety show where she watched a video of you
仅此而已，在演播室录制期间骑着银河河马的牛仔竞技表演。
rodeo riding a Galactic Hippo during a studio taping, that's all.
G-银河河马？
G-Galactic Hippo?
嗯，就是这样吗？我真的想不起来了…嗯？！
Hmm, was that what it was? I can't really recall... Huh?!
-哇。-Kaname，尴尬的过去。
- Wow. - Kaname, embarrassing past.
住手！
Cut it out!
起泡苹果酒？不，谢谢。
Sparkling apple cider? No thanks.
为什么不呢？它很好吃。
Why not? It's tasty.
她一直在喝苹果牛奶。
All she's been drinking is apple milk.
我知道！她处理不了这些问题。
I know! She can't handle the fizzles.
真是个婴儿！
What a baby!
我得说，我们村的苹果是Gori Gori很棒！
I gotta say, our village's apples are Gori-Gori great!
对吧，海亚特？
Right, Hayate?
是的，戈里·戈里肯定。
Yeah, Gori-Gori for sure.
等等，你是Freyja的男朋友吗？！
Wait, are you Freyja's boyfriend?!
真正地但他不是地球人吗？
Really? But isn't he an Earthling?
W-什么。。。？
W-Wha...?
不，我和海亚特不是那样的。。。！
No, me and Hayate aren't like that...!
那么地球上的风是什么味道？
So what's an Earth|ing's wind taste like?
妻子一直在谈论想要孩子。
Wife's been talking about wanting kids.
嗯，越快越好。
Well, the sooner the better.
然后是第二个和第三个。
Then it's on to the second and third one.
这是怎么一回事？
What is it?
哦，只是。。。
Oh, it's just...
这里的每个人都很年轻。。。
Everyone here really is so young...
Windermerian的平均寿命为30年。
The average lifespan of a Windermerian is 3O years.
围绕这些部分，
Around these parts,
孩子五岁时就种下自己的树苗。
a child plants their own sapling at the age of five.
记住，这个星球上的人们与我们截然不同。
Remember, the people of this planet are very different from us.
市长先生。
Mister Mayor.
谢谢你，先生，
Thank you sir,
欢迎Freyja像这样回家。
for welcoming Freyja home like this.
-同样地，看到弗雷亚如此高兴——背叛是一种死罪。
- Likewise, seeing Freyja so happ- - Defection is a capital offense.
感谢海因茨陛下的仁慈。
Be thankful for His Majesty Heinz's mercy.
是的，我完全理解。
Yes, I fully understand.
你为什么提起这个？Freyja唱歌是为了带来和平！
Why'r_e you bringing that up? Freyja sang to bring peace!
你在这方面没有发言权，局外人。
You have no say in this, outsider.
你说什么？！
What did you say?!
嘿，你们怎么了？！
Hey, what's with you guys?!
退后！
Back off!
别胡说了！
Stop this nonsense!
派对结束了！
Party's over!
在这一点上与外星人交谈有什么用？！
What use is talking to aliens at this point?!
我们应该把他们赶出去！
We should be running them out!
根据陛下的命令，我的任务是保护你。
By order of His Majesty, I'm tasked to protect you.
尽管我完全同意那些人。
Even though I completely agree with those men.
-什么？！-坚持住。让他来处理这件事。
- What?! - Hold it. Let him handle this.
你扰乱了和平。
You're disturbing the peace.
骑士爵士！
Sir Knight!
去死吧Walkijlre！
To hell with Walkijlre!
他们在我们的风中唱着肮脏的歌！
They're spewing their filthy songs in our wind!
不管你喜不喜欢，他们都是陛下的客人。
Like it or not, they are His Majesty's guests.
你的意思是反对你的国王吗？
Do you mean to oppose your king?
请稍等。
Just a moment please.
-约翰神父？-约翰神父！
- Father Johann? - Father Johann!
约翰神父！
Father Johann!
约翰神父？
Father Johann?
约翰·温利（Johann Winly）。
Johann Winly.
侍奉风之神的祭司之一。
One of the priests who serve the God of the Wind.
拜托，你能原谅这些人的冒犯吗？
Please, could you possibly forgive these men for their offense?
约翰神父。。。
Father Johann...
如你所愿。
As you wish.
谢谢你。
You have my thanks.
你们三个现在该走了。
You three should leave for now.
W-我们会的。
W-We Will.
谢谢你，约翰神父。
Thank you, Father Johann.
我希望你能原谅我的打扰。
I hope you will forgive my intrusion.
不，你真的救了我们。
No, you really saved us.
所以你是Mikumo Guynemer，明星歌手。
So you are Mikumo Guynemer, Singer of the Stars.
我是WalkUre的Mikumo Guynemer，
Iam Mikumo Guynemer of WalkUre,
再也没有了。
nothing more.
是的，当然。请原谅我。
Yes, of course. Do forgive me.
弗雷娅·维恩。
Freyja Wion.
昨天是我最近第一次听到你唱歌。
Yesterday was the first time I've heard you sing in a while.
我记得每次我访问这个村庄时都受到你的歌曲的欢迎。
I remember being welcomed by your songs every time I visited this village.
我希望你继续把你优美的嗓音添加到风中。
I hope you continue to add your fine voice to the wind.
你，你说对了！
Y-You betcha!
弗雷亚！你的礼貌在哪里？那不是和约翰神父说话的方式！
Freyja! Where are your manners? That's no way to talk to Father Johann!
哦
Oh!
哦，我错过了这里的风的颜色。
Oh, I missed the color of the wind here.
到春天结束时，这个地方将盛开苹果花。
By the end of Spring, this place will be blooming with apple blossoms.
到处都是白色的小花！
Little white flowers everywhere!
我真的很想给你看，海亚特。
I'd really like to show you, Hayate.
是的，我希望有一天能看到它。
Yeah, I'd like to see it someday.
你从哪里弄到这样一张旧照片的？真可爱。他们俩独自一人在果园里。
Where did you get an old picture like that anyway? That's so cute. The two of them off alone in the orchard.
真可爱。他们俩独自一人在果园里。
That's so cute. The two of them off alone in the orchard.
我是一个没有限制的女人。真可爱。他们俩独自一人在果园里。
I am a woman without limits. That's so cute. The two of them off alone in the orchard.
我是一个没有限制的女人。
I am a woman without limits.
我是一个没有限制的女人。隐马尔可夫模型？
I am a woman without limits. Hmm?
还有什么事困扰着你吗？
Something else bothering you?
风雪人和地球人是不可能配对的。
It's an impossible pairing, Windermerians and Earthlings.
你怎么能这么肯定？
How can you be so certain?
我的家人被地球人杀害了。
My family was killed by Earthlings.
我们村也经历过战争。事实上
Our village has known war as well. And there's the fact that
我们的寿命与地球人的寿命不同。
our life span is different than that of Earthlings.
说实话，村民们都很担心
To tell the truth, the villagers are all worried
总有一天，这会给你们和Freyja带来悲伤。
that one day this will bring sorrow to you folks and Freyja.
即便如此，总有一天，所有的风都会合而为一。
Even so, one day all winds will be as one.
找到了！
Found it!
我回来了。
I'm home.
这就是你的树，弗雷娅？
So this is your tree, Freyja?
不，它是我奶奶的。
No, it's my grandma's.
我从没见过她，但这棵树
I never met her, but this tree
是这里最古老的，苹果味道最好。
is the oldest one here, with the best-tasting apples.
太好了！
It's so good!
正当
Right?
然后你周围的小树就是我种的。
And then the smaller trees around you are the ones I planted.
哦
Oh.
山顶上的那个是我妈妈的，
The one atop that hill is my mom's,
后面那个是我爸爸的。
and the one back there is my dad's.
我妈妈变得随风而动
My mom became one with the wind
当我三岁的时候，我的父亲就在上次战争之后。
when I was three, and my dad just after the last war.
我懂了。
I see.
我想我父亲去世时我大约十岁。
I think I was about ten when my old man died.
你说他是飞行员。
You said he was a pilot.
我也跟你说过阿拉德司令，对吧？
I told you about Commander Arad too, right?
是的，他是你父亲的下属。
Yes, he was your father's subordinate.
这是正确的。
That's right.
当我不知道该怎么做的时候，他招募我当飞行员。
He recruited me to be a pilot when I didn't know what to do with myself.
我仍然清晰地记得，我的第一次单人飞行。
I still remember it vividly, my first solo flight.
我当时就感觉到了。。。
I felt it right then...
我和爸爸在一起的感觉。
The feeling that I was with my dad.
他有点古怪。
He was kind of an eccentric guy.
总是从他驻扎的地方发送手写信件，
Always sending hand written letters from where he was stationed,
每个都有一个随机短语。
each with a single random phrase.
比如什么？
Like what?
这样地。
Like this.
“天空广阔。”
"The sky is vast."
天空是。。。
The sky is...
天空是广阔的！
The sky is vast!
“雨水的味道。”
"Scent of the rain."
“星星充满了夜晚。”
"Stars fill the night."
水果st/l/绿色是一种
A fruit st/l/ green is one
被吸引是二
Being attracted is two
我的心在燃烧
My heart is burning
弗雷亚”
Freyia"
一个承诺就是三个
A promise is three
被拔毛是四个
Being plucked is four
穿越天涯海角
Traveling the sky's end
明星们一定也很悲伤
The stars must be sad too
星星也一定很悲伤“云形如山”
The stars must be sad too "Clouds shaped like mountains."
明星们一定也很悲伤
The stars must be sad too
第五，后腿长得很好而且不稳/
Five, rears well up and fal/
第五，后腿长得很好，fal/“大海是蓝色的。”
Five, rears well up and fal/ "The sea is blue."
第五，后腿长得很好而且不稳/
Five, rears well up and fal/
第五，养得很好，说：“沙漠很热。”
Five, rears well up and fal/ "The desert is hot."
第五，后腿长得很好而且不稳/
Five, rears well up and fal/
想念那些逝去的人
Missing those that are gone
怀念那些逝去的“银河系是巨大的”
Missing those that are gone "The galaxy is huge."
想念那些逝去的人
Missing those that are gone
让我们唱一首祈祷歌
Let us sing a song of prayer, that it
到达这片l/ghz海的遥远海岸
reaches the far shores of this sea of l/ghz'
红色应用程序、小型应用程序
Red app/es, small app/es
转/笔和改变颜色的喜悦
Bits of joy that r/pen and change color
让我们一个接一个
Lez' us oounz' them one by one
看到这些面孔
to see the faces
我们所爱的人
of those we love
这是一首流传了好几代的温德曼传奇歌曲。
That was a Windermerian song of legend, passed down for generations.
这是关于一个乡村女孩和来自星空的风神的故事。
It's about a village girl and the God of the Wind who came from across the stars.
一首苦乐参半的情歌。
A bittersweet love song.
我爱你，弗雷娅！
I love you, Freyia!
我想一起生活！
I want to live our lives out together!
你知道苹果花只开十天吗？
Did you know that apple blossoms only bloom for ten days?
它们开花了，马上就凋谢了。
They burst into bloom, and fall right away.
你真的同意吗？
Are you really okay with that?
有一朵像我一样的苹果花吗？
With an apple flower like me?
我爱你，不管你是什么样的人！
I love you Freyja, however you are!
谢谢你，海亚特。
Thank you, Hayate.
我也。。。
I also...
什么
What?
闪耀着是的，飞入黑暗面
Shining e yes, fai/ into the dark side
闪亮是的，fai/进入黑暗面那是从哪里来的？
Shining e yes, fai/ into the dark side Where's that coming from?
闪耀着是的，飞入黑暗面
Shining e yes, fai/ into the dark side
闪耀着，是的，飞入黑暗面风中有扰动。
Shining e yes, fai/ into the dark side There's a disturbance in the wind.
闪耀着是的，飞入黑暗面
Shining e yes, fai/ into the dark side
闪亮是的，fai/进入黑暗面时态，等等边缘，但它有点。。。
Shining e yes, fai/ into the dark side Tense, so on edge, but it kinda...
紧张，等等，但有点。。。
Tense, so on edge, but it kinda...
我可以'2'再次回到PATH 0F HU/N时态，等等，但它有点。。。
I can '2' go back again THE PA TH 0F HU/N Tense, so on edge, but it kinda...
我可以'2'再次返回PATH 0F HU/N
I can '2' go back again THE PA TH 0F HU/N
我可以'2'再次返回PATH 0F HU/N…听起来像Kumo Kumo。
I can '2' go back again THE PA TH 0F HU/N ...Sounds like Kumo-Kumo.
我可以'2'再次返回PATH 0F HU/N
I can '2' go back again THE PA TH 0F HU/N
我可以'2'再回去一次PATH 0F HU/N这首歌…可能吗？
I can '2' go back again THE PA TH 0F HU/N This singing... ls it possible?
这首歌……可能吗？
This singing... ls it possible?
这是一场战争，这首歌……可能吗？
A war/d played our through this This singing... ls it possible?
一场战争在这场战争中扮演了我们的角色
A war/d played our through this
一场战争通过这扇折叠门打响了我们？！
A war/d played our through this A Fold Gate?!
一场战争在这场战争中扮演了我们的角色
A war/d played our through this
一场战争让我们度过了这不可能！Windermere被维度故障隔离！
A war/d played our through this Impossible! Windermere is isolated by a dimensional fault!
Moonl/jghz引导旋律
Moonl/jghz' guided melody
moonl/jghz的引导旋律不可能直接折叠到大气中。
moonl/jghz' guided melody Folding directly into the atmosphere isn't possible.
等着看吧
Wait to see
OU/E TL Y发生了什么
whatis going on OU/E TL Y
DES THUG T/ON的调子是…S0 don'z’look back
THE TUNE OF DES THUG T/ON IS... S0 don 'z' look back
毁灭的调子是。--0美元don 7回头看，一个身份不明的sh/jo出现在Raven草地上-
THE TUNE OF DESTRUCTION IS. - - $0 don 7 look back A n unidentified sh/jo has appeared abo ve Ra ven grass-
Ha vengrass上方出现了一个未确认的sh/p。
An unidentified sh/p has appeared above Ha vengrass.
躺在那里等待革命的机会一个不明身份的人出现在哈文格拉斯的上空。
Lying in wait for a chance a2' revolution An unidentified sh/p has appeared above Ha vengrass.
埋伏等待革命的机会
Lying in wait for a chance at revolution
躺在床上等待机会2'革命放大图像！
Lying in wait for a chance a2' revolution Magnifying image!
埋伏等待革命的机会
Lying in wait for a chance at revolution
进入你的体内，那是……一艘Macross级飞船？！
Into you, That's... a Macross class ship?!
那是……一艘Macross级飞船？！
That's... a Macross class ship?!
我们的NOT是不可能的那是……一艘Macross级飞船？！
There is no way our NOT YET That's... a Macross class ship?!
我们还没有办法
There is no way our NOT YET
我们的NOT YET l2'似乎没有任何修改。
there is no wa y our NOT YET l2' appears to have been hea vi/y modified.
L2’似乎已进行了重大修改。
L2' appears to have been hea vi/y modified.
唤醒l2'时的Wa/z'似乎已被heavi/y修改。
Wa/z' for the time of awakening l2' appears to have been hea vi/y modified.
Wa/z'代表觉醒的时间
Wa/z' for the time of awakening
Wa/z'代表觉醒的时间无法识别它的起源。
Wa/z' for the time of awakening Unable to identify its orig/n.
Wa/z'代表觉醒的时间
Wa/z' for the time of awakening
Wa/z’代表觉醒的时间，非常好。争夺空中骑士
Wa/z' for the time of awakening Very well. Scramble the Aerial Knights
很好。争夺空中骑士
Very well. Scramble the Aerial Knights
安静/y，安静/y很好。争夺空中骑士
quiet/y, quiet/y Very well. Scramble the Aerial Knights
（70/61/14安静/年
(70/61/14 quiet/y
安静/y，安静/y并推出Sigur Berrentz！
quiet/y, quiet/y and launch the Sigur Berrentzs!
必须准备好让主反应堆功率增加！
Gotta be ready to rock Main reactor power output increasing!
也许…你能，只有你能
Maybe... On/y you can, only you can
也许……只有你能，只有你能从事人工Grav/tyl
Maybe... Only you can, only you can Engaging artificial gra v/tyl
也许…你能，只有你能
Maybe... On/y you can, only you can
也许……你可以，只有你才能乘坐Sigur Berrentz航班！
Maybe... On/y you can, only you can Sigur Berrentzs taking flight!
Sigur Berrentz正在飞行！
Sigur Berrentzs taking flight!
让我震惊Sigur Berrentz的飞行！
Rock me Sigur Berrentzs taking flight!
Sigur Berrentz正在飞行！
Sigur Berrentzs taking flight!
我知道你能，我知道你可以坐西格尔·贝伦茨的飞机！
I know you can, I know you can Sigur Berrentzs taking flight!
我知道你可以，我知道你能
I know you can, I know you can
只有你能，只有你能
Only you can, only you can
摇晃我
rock me
7'0黑暗，走向黑暗
7'0 the darkness, to the darkness
去摇滚吧，准备摇滚吧！
Heady to rock, get ready to rock!
C0u/7fd0W/7发给HU/N，是的！
C0u/7fd0W/7 TO HU/N, YES!
去摇滚吧，准备摇滚吧！
Heady to rock, get ready to rock!
立即释放它
Unleash it now
准备好摇滚了
Gonna be ready to rock
准备好引爆未知敌方部署战斗机！
Gonna be ready to rock Unknown hostile deploying fighters!
未知敌方部署战斗机！
Unknown hostile deploying fighters!
该死的侵略者！
Damn invaders!
进入你的体内，该死的入侵者！
Into you Damn invaders!
进入你的内心
Into you
让我们g0！
Let's g0!
准备好摇滚了
Gonna be ready to rock
准备好车了，这是第三个订单。现在加入您！
Gonna be ready to rook This is the 3rd Order. Joining you now!
这是第三个订单。现在加入您！
This is the 3rd Order. Joining you now!
准备好了，准备好了！这是第三个订单。现在加入您！
Gonna be ready to, be ready to rock! This is the 3rd Order. Joining you now!
准备好了，准备好了！
Gonna be ready to, be ready to rock!
准备好了，准备好了！爸爸！
Gonna be ready to, be ready to rock! Da!
准备好了，准备好了！
Gonna be ready to, be ready to rock!
准备好了，准备好了！目标/绑定。/无法识别？这是一个未知的飞行高度-
Gonna be ready to, be ready to rock! Target /nbound./ Unable to identify? It's an unknown f/ght—
准备好了，准备好了！
Gonna be ready to, be ready to rock!
准备好了，准备好了！提奥！
Gonna be ready to, be ready to rock! Theo!
提奥！
Theo!
提奥！大家散开！
Theo! Everyone spread out!
-Xao/-我还是g00d/
- Xao/ - I'm still g00d./
那么好吧。。。
Alright then...
明白了！
Gotcha!
是的，各位，现在是表演时间。
Yeah everybody, it's showtime.
就在这里，嘿，现在走
RIGHT HERE, hey go now
联合国摧毁，LE T15’Hock！典当！
UN TO DESTRUCTION, LE T15' Hock! Hock!
是的，AL WA Y8只是000/，
Yeah AL WA Y8 just be 000/,
是的，AL WA Y8刚刚达到000/，它躲过了他们？！
Yeah AL WA Y8 just be 000/, It dodged them?!
是的，AL WA Y8只是000/，
Yeah AL WA Y8 just be 000/,
我知道也许你是r/lghz
I know that maybe you're r/lghz'
/我要走了没有没有没有没有！
/'m gonnamNo N0 N0 N0!
/我要走了没有没有没有没有！各位，在教堂里避难。
/'m gonnamNo N0 N0 N0! Everyone, take shelter inside the church.
各位，在教堂里避难。
Everyone, take shelter inside the church.
说吧，说吧，大家都躲到教堂里去。
Say na na na na, what you say Everyone, take shelter inside the church.
说不，说不，你说什么
Say na na na na, what you say
/你会成为我的，娜！不！不！不！
/'m gonna make you mine, Na! Na! Na! Na!
/你会成为我的，娜！不！不！不！无法到达以太或拉格纳。
/'m gonna make you mine, Na! Na! Na! Na! Can't reach either the Aether or Ragna.
/你会成为我的，娜！不！不！不！
/'m gonna make you mine, Na! Na! Na! Na!
/你会成为我的，娜！不！不！不！那首歌干扰了所有的Fold通讯？
/'m gonna make you mine, Na! Na! Na! Na! That song is jamming all Fold communications?
那首歌干扰了所有的Fold通讯？
That song is jamming all Fold communications?
你疯了吗？永远不要让你走那首歌干扰了所有的Fold通讯？
Are you crazy? Never let you go That song is jamming all Fold communications?
你疯了吗？永远不要让你走
Are you crazy? Never let you go
你得了i2'，永远不知道，牺牲短程通信仍在工作。
You got i2', never know, in sacrifice Short range comms are still working.
你在牺牲中得到了i2'，永远不知道
You got i2', never know, in sacrifice
你得了i2'，不知道，在牺牲中，我正在远程呼叫Siggies。
You got i2', never know, in sacrifice I'm calling in the Siggies by remote.
我正在远程呼叫Siggies。
I'm calling in the Siggies by remote.
（是/知道/知道）我正在远程呼叫Siggies。
(Yes / know, / know) I'm calling in the Siggies by remote.
（是的，我知道，我知道）
(Yes I know, I know)
（是的，我知道，我知道）Fold Sound Link运输/按计划进行。
(Yes I know, I know) Fold Sound Link transit/on on schedule.
Fold Sound Link运输/按计划进行。
Fold Sound Link transit/on on schedule.
到底怎么回事？您的r/jghz'Fold Sound Link正在按计划传输。
What the hell is going on? You're r/jghz' Fold Sound Link transit/on on schedule.
到底怎么回事？你是r/jghz
What the hell is going on? You're r/jghz'
0美元疯狂，分解，分解
$0 crazy, break it down, break it down, break it down
你是认真的吗？也许吧，妈妈/
Are you serious? Maybe, ma ybe...0h/
让它成为现实
Just make it a reality
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say?
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？什么
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say? What?!
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say?
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？啊…什么？
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say? Ugh... What?
啊…什么？
Ugh... What?
我知道你想要什么啊…什么？
I know what you want Ugh... What?
你是唯一的，带我去吧
You 're the only one, take me h/jgher
给我打电话，黑暗的含义是什么？
Tel/ me, Whafs the meaning of darkness, darkness?
没有出路，让我告诉你
N0 way out, let me tell you
0小时！哦给我带路，0h不可能，不可能我们的
0h! Oh! Show me the way, 0h no way, no way our
0小时！哦给我带路，哦，不行，我们的Freyja！
0h! Oh! Show me the way, 0h no way, no way our Freyja!
0小时！哦给我带路，0h不可能，不可能我们的
0h! Oh! Show me the way, 0h no way, no way our
0小时！哦给我带路，哦，不行，我们的Freyja！
0h! Oh! Show me the way, 0h no way, no way our Freyja!
这首歌是什么？
What is this song?
它正在影响我们的生物折叠受体！
It's affecting our Bio-Fold Receptors!
新当选的
Incoming!
是的，各位，现在是表演时间。
Yeah everybody, it's showtime.
就在这里，嘿，现在走
RIGHT HERE, hey go now
联合国摧毁，LE T15’Hock！典当！
UN TO DESTRUCTION, LE T15' Hock! Hock!
是的，AL WA Y8只是000/，
Yeah AL WA Y8 just be 000/,
我知道也许你是r/lghz
I know that maybe you're r/lghz'
/我要走了没有没有没有没有！
/'m gonnamNo N0 N0 N0!
说不，说不，你说什么
Say na na na na, what you say
/你会成为我的，娜！不！不！不！
/'m gonna make you mine, Na! Na! Na! Na!
你疯了吗？永远不要让你走
Are you crazy? Never let you go
你在牺牲中得到了i2'，永远不知道
You got i2', never know, in sacrifice
（是的，我知道，我知道）
(Yes I know, I know)
到底怎么回事？你是r/jghz
What the hell is going on? You're r/jghz'
0美元疯狂，分解，分解
$0 crazy, break it down, break it down, break it down
0美元疯狂，打破它自己，打破它，打破它-苹果…！-弗雷亚！
$0 crazy, break it do wn, break it down, break it down - The apples...! - Freyja!
你是认真的吗？也许吧，妈妈…哦/苹果！每个人都有苹果！
Are you serious? Maybe, ma ybe...0h/ The apples! Everyone's apples!
你是认真的吗？也许吧，妈妈/
Are you serious? Maybe, ma ybe...0h/
你是认真的吗？也许吧，妈妈…哦/不要！
Are you serious? Maybe, ma ybe...0h/ Don't!
你是认真的吗？也许吧，妈妈/
Are you serious? Maybe, ma ybe...0h/
你是认真的吗？也许吧，妈妈…哦/我爸爸的！我妈妈的！
Are you serious? Maybe, ma ybe...0h/ My dad's! My mom's!
我爸爸的！我妈妈的！
MY dad's! My mom's!
让它成为现实吧我爸爸的！我妈妈的！
Just make it a reality My dad's! My mom's!
让它成为现实
Just make it a reality
让它成为现实吧不！他们不能！他们不能！
Just make it a reality No! They can't! They can't!
不他们不能！他们不能！
No! They can't! They can't!
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？不他们不能！他们不能！
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say? No! They can't! They can't!
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say?
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？控制住自己！
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say? Get a hold of yourself!
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say?
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？你认为如果你死在这里，你的父母会很高兴吗？！
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say? You think your mom and dad would be happy if you died here?!
你认为如果你死在这里，你的父母会很高兴吗？！
You think your mom and dad would be happy if you died here?!
/知道你想要什么你认为如果你死在这里，你的父母会很高兴吗？！
/ know what you want You think your mom and dad would be happy if you died here?!
你认为如果你死在这里，你的父母会很高兴吗？！
You think your mom and dad would be happy if you died here?!
你是唯一的一个，带我去吧。你认为如果你死在这里，你的父母会很高兴吗？！
You 're the only one, take me h/jgher You think your mom and dad would be happy if you died here?!
你是唯一的，带我去吧
You 're the only one, take me h/jgher
给我打电话，黑暗的含义是什么？我不会让他们这样做的。
Tel/ me, Whafs the meaning of darkness, darkness? I won't let them do this.
给我打电话，黑暗的含义是什么？
Tel/ me, Whafs the meaning of darkness, darkness?
当悲伤传来时，我会告诉你
N0 wa y out, lez' me tel/ you When the sadness f/ow/ng through ones hearz'
当悲伤穿过心扉时
When the sadness f/ow/ng through ones heart
像刀一样切，
cuts like a knife,
像刀一样切，唱歌？
cuts like a knife, Singing?
像刀一样切，
Cuts like a knife,
它留下了一个开放的伤口Mikumo！
it leaves an open wound Mikumo!
它留下了一个开放的伤口
It leaves an open wound
留下了一个开放的伤口他们在动摇？！
it leaves an open wound They're wavering?!
它留下了一个开放的伤口
It leaves an open wound
我看到它留下了一个开放的伤口。
it leaves an open wound I see.
我们必须尽可能破坏敌人的生物折叠波！
We have to disrupt the enemy's Bio-Fold Waves as much as possible!
奋斗了多久？我们必须尽可能破坏敌人的生物折叠波！
For how /ong have / struggled? We have to disrupt the enemy's Bio-Fold Waves as much as possible!
我挣扎了多久？
For how /ong have I struggled?
我挣扎了多久？就在你后面！
For how /ong have I struggled? Right behind you!
我挣扎了多久？
For how /ong have I struggled?
出口不见了
The exit is nowhere to be found
出口无处可寻别担心我们！去
The exit is nowhere to be found Don't worry about us! Go!
别担心我们！去
Don't worry about us! Go!
没有时间害怕，不要担心我们！去
N0 time to be afraid, Don't worry about us! Go!
没有时间害怕，
N0 time to be afraid,
没有时间害怕，很好。走吧！
N0 time to be afraid, Very well. Let's go!
没有时间害怕，
N0 time to be afraid,
没有时间害怕了，-噢，先生！-是的，先生！
N0 time to be afraid, - Oorah sir! - Yes sir!
-噢，先生！-是的，先生！
- Oorah sir! - Yes sir!
因为时间不等人-噢，先生！-是的，先生！
Because time waits for no one - Oorah sir! - Yes sir!
因为时间不等人
Because time waits for no one
因为时间不等人罗根
because time waits for no one Rogen
因为时间不等人
because time waits for no one
因为时间不等人Freyja。。。
because time waits for no one Freyja...
因为时间不等人
because time waits for no one
因为时间不等人，我会没事的。开始做
because time waits for no one I'll be fine. Get going!
剥下你内心深处的痂，
Peel off that scab deep in your heart,
赤手空拳
with your own bare hands
迈向一个勇敢的新世界，NEX 7'！
Onward to a brave new world, NEX 7'!
迈向一个勇敢的新世界，NEX 7'！三角洲航班'，给我！
Onward to a brave new world, NEX 7'! Delta Flight', f0//ow me!
迈向一个勇敢的新世界，NEX 7'！
Onward to a brave new world, NEX 7'!
迈向一个勇敢的新世界，NEX 7'！隐马尔可夫模型？
Onward to a brave new world, NEX 7'! Hmm?
迈向一个勇敢的新世界，NEX 7'！
Onward to a brave new world, NEX 7'!
苦难仍在继续。所以……终于开始唱歌了，嗯，沃尔基尔？现在你会怎么回应，警报器？
Misery ongoing. So... Finally started singing eh, Walkiire? Now how will you respond, Siren?
所以……终于开始唱歌了，嗯，沃尔基尔？现在你会怎么回应，警报器？
So... Finally started singing eh, Walkiire? Now how will you respond, Siren?
L2仍然很痛所以……终于开始唱歌了，嗯，Walkille？现在你会怎么回应，警报器？
L2' still hurts like hell So... Finally started singing eh, Walkilre? Now how will you respond, Siren?
所以……终于开始唱歌了，嗯，沃尔基尔？现在你会怎么回应，警报器？
So... Finally started singing eh, Walkiire? Now how will you respond, Siren?
在狂风中撕咬你的船舷（去过那里，就这么做！）所以……终于开始唱歌了，嗯，沃尔基尔？现在你会怎么回应，警报器？
Biting your l/ps against the blasting wind (been there, done that!) So... Finally started singing eh, Walkiire? Now how will you respond, Siren?
在狂风中咬着嘴唇（一直在那里，做了！）
Biting your lips against the blasting wind (been there, done that!)
在狂风中撕碎你的谎言（一直在那里，做到了！）他们袭击了Freyja的村庄。我不会让他们逍遥法外的！
Biting your lies against the blasting wind (been there, done that!) They attacked Freyja's village. I won't let them get away with this!
他们袭击了Freyja的村庄。我不会让他们逍遥法外的！
They attacked Freyja's village. I won't let them get away with this!
越过l/m/z'，走向i2'。他们袭击了Freyja的村庄。我不会让他们逍遥法外的！
Over the l/m/z', go for i2'. Pulse thumping They attacked Freyja's village. I won't let them get away with this!
越过l/m/z'，走向i2'。脉冲重击
Over the l/m/z', go for i2'. Pulse thumping
越过l/m/z'，走向i2'。脉搏沉重，冷静下来。首先使用MHVm/ssi/es。
Over the l/m/z', go for i2'. Pulse thumping Calm down. Use your MHVm/ssi/es first.
G0超越了我已经知道的消失点！
G0 beyond the vanishing point I know already!
G0超出消失点
G0 beyond the vanishing point
这个像野兽一样重新打开伤口厕所
The! reopened wound loo/rs like a beast
说不，说不，你说什么
Say na na na na, what you say
/你会成为我的，娜！不！不！不！
/'m gonna make you mine, Na! Na! Na! Na!
你疯了吗？永远不要让你走
Are you crazy? Never let you go
你疯了吗？永远别让你走他们躲过了MR Vs 7/
Are you crazy? Never lez' you go They dodged the MR Vs 7/
你在牺牲中得到了i2'，永远不知道，该死，他们可以移动！
You got i2', never know, in sacrifice Damn, they can move!
你在牺牲中得到了i2'，永远不知道
You got i2', never know, in sacrifice
你在牺牲Delta 5中得了2分，永远不知道！在您的s/X上/
You got i2', never know, in sacrifice Delta 5! On your s/X/
你在牺牲中得到了i2'，永远不知道
You got i2', never know, in sacrifice
你永远都不知道，牺牲是不可能的！
You got i2', never know, in sacrifice Impossible!
不可能的
Impossible!
（是的，我知道，我知道）不可能！
(Yes I know, I know) Impossible!
（是的，我知道，我知道）
(Yes I know, I know)
到底怎么回事？你是r/jghz，这些未知的怪物正在发射强大的折叠波！
What the hell is going on? You're r/jghz' Strong Fold Wave are emitting from these unknown bogeys!
0美元疯狂，分解，分解
$0 crazy, break it down, break it down, break it down
0美元疯了，把它分解，分解，分解他们是一种新型的幽灵！
$0 crazy, break it down, break it down, break it down They're some new type of Ghost!
0美元疯狂，分解，分解
$0 crazy, break it down, break it down, break it down
0美元疯了，把它分解，分解，分解G-Ghosts？！即使如此，他们的机动方式。。。
$0 crazy, break it down, break it down, break it down G-Ghosts?! Even so, the way they maneuver...
你是认真的吗？也许吧，妈妈/
Are you serious? Maybe, ma ybe...0h/
你是认真的吗？也许吧，也许吧……0h/Sigur Berrentz的主炮占85%！
Are you serious? Maybe, ma ybe...0h/ Sigur Berrentzs main guns at 85%!
Sigur Berrentz主炮占85%！
Sigur Berrentzs main guns at 85%!
让它成为现实吧，Sigur Berrentz的主炮占85%！
Just make it a reality Sigur Berrentzs main guns at 85%!
让它成为现实
Just make it a reality
让它成为现实吧，a//战斗机清除Sigur Berrentzs的火！
Just make it a reality A// fighters clear the Sigur Berrentzs ' //ne of fire!
A//战斗机清除Sigur Berrentz的火力线！
A// fighters clear the Sigur Berrentzs ' line of fire!
0美元疯狂，疯狂，退出。/你怎么说？A//战斗机清除Sigur Berrentz的火力线！
$0 crazy, crazy, get 0ut./ What do you say? A// fighters clear the Sigur Berrentzs ' line of fire!
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say?
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？海因茨国王！
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say? King Heinz!
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say?
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？大家欢呼国王！
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say? All hail the King!
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say?
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？电费补偿！火线已全部清除！
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say? Energy charge comp/ere! Line of fire is all clear!
电费补偿！火线已全部清除！
Energy charge comp/ere! Line of fire is all clear!
我知道你想要什么样的电费补偿！火线已全部清除！
I know what you wam' Energy charge comp/ere! Line of fire is all clear!
电费补偿！火线已全部清除！
Energy charge comp/ere! Line of fire is all clear!
你是唯一的一个，带我去看看h/jgher Energy charge comp/ere！火线已全部清除！
You 're the only one, take me h/jgher Energy charge comp/ere! Line of fire is all clear!
你是唯一的，带我去吧
You 're the only one, take me h/jgher
你是唯一的一个，带我去h/jgher Fire！
You 're the only one, take me h/jgher Fire!
你是唯一的，带我去吧
You 're the only one, take me h/jgher
给我打电话，黑暗的含义是什么？
Tel/ me, Whafs the meaning of darkness, darkness?
给我打电话，黑暗的含义是什么？敌人旗舰主炮开火！
Tel/ me, Whafs the meaning of darkness, darkness? Enemy flagship main guns firing!
没有出路，让我告诉你
N0 way out, let me tell you
没有出路，让我告诉你提高维度障碍。
N0 way out, let me tell you Raise Dimensional Barrier.
没有出路，让我告诉你
N0 way out, let me tell you
0小时！哦给我带路，0h不可能，不可能我们的
0h! Oh! Show me the way, 0h no way, no way our
抓住他们了！
Got 'em!
倒霉！
Shit!
敌人sh/p完好无损。
Enemy sh/p intact.
大概准备发射他们的主炮。
Presumably preparing to fire their main cannon.
Sigur Berrentzs，封锁起来！
Sigur Berrentzs, barriers up!
日分！开火后我们没有足够的动力！
Bu! we don't have enough power after firing the main guns!
那就别无选择！
Then there's no choice!
De Enda公司
De Enda
De Enda（U/ano）
De Enda U/ano
尊敬的陛下！
De Enda U/ano Your Majesty!
De Enda（U/ano）
De Enda U/ano
风之歌太紧张了。。。
De Enda U/ano The Wind Song is too much strain...
De g/ada押韵k/an De/kez。。。
De g/ada rhyms k/an de/kez...
De g/ada rhyms k/an De/kez……看在陛下的份上，不要让他们开枪！
De g/ada rhyms k/an de/kez... For His Majesty's sake, don't let them fire their main gun!
De g/ada押韵k/an De/kez。。。
De g/ada rhyms k/an de/kez...
De g/ada押韵k/an De/kez…Dal
De g/ada rhyms k/an de/kez... Dal
勒德拉姆
Le de raam /om
Le de ream/om Delta Flight来了！
Le de ream /om Delta Flight is here to ass/st!
勒德拉姆
Le de raam /om
K/ano K/ano de aura公司
K/ano k/ano de aura
K/ano K/ano de aura-拿着这个！-拿着这个！
K/ano k/ano de aura - Take this! - Take this!
K/ano K/ano de aura公司
K/ano k/ano de aura
-那些东西分离了？！-。“准备好了”！
-Those things detached?! -.S'preaa' out'!
他们无处不在/
They're everywhere./
该死！
Dammit!
Xao！
Xao!
不能打他们！不好的。。。
Can't hit 'em! Not good...
De Enda公司
De Enda
De Enda（U/ano）
De Enda U/ano
立即执行De Enda U/ano。
De Enda U/ano Now.
De Enda（U/ano）
De Enda U/ano
De g/ada押韵k/an-
De g/ada rhyms k/an-
…A//rig/n；De g/ada押韵k/an-
...A// rig/n; De g/ada rhyms k/an-
…A//r/ghr，
...A// r/ghr,
我知道你不会回头所以不要回头
I know you don't /ook back So don 'z' /ook back
…/om
.../om
K/ano K/ano de aura公司
K/ano k/ano de aura
De fa/lo yoo z/am公司
De fa/lo yoo z/am
Tres degna zu/a公司
Tres degna zu/a
Tres degna zu/a所以这是风之力量的歌手。。。
Tres degna zu/a So this is the Singer of the Wind's power...
所以这就是风之歌的力量。。。
So this is the Singer of the Wind's power...
De/k…所以这是风的力量的歌手。。。
De/k... So this is the Singer of the Wind's power...
取消/取消。。。
De/k...
De/k…但现在结束了。
De/k... But this ends now.
你是认真的吗？也许吧，妈妈/
Are you serious? Maybe, ma ybe...0h/
让它成为现实
Just make it a reality
S0疯了，抓住我们！你怎么说？别让他们通过！
S0 crazy crazy, get our! What do you say? Don't let them through!
S0疯了，抓住我们！你怎么说？
S0 crazy crazy, get our! What do you say?
S0疯了，抓住我们！你怎么说？罗杰！
S0 crazy crazy, get our! What do you say? Roger!
S0疯了，抓住我们！你怎么说？
S0 crazy crazy, get our! What do you say?
我知道你想要什么
I know what you want
你是唯一的，带我去吧
You 're the only one, take me h/jgher
你是唯一的一个，带我去哈/jgher Kassim！
You 're the only one, take me h/jgher Kassim!
给我打电话，黑暗的含义是什么？
Tel/ me, Whafs the meaning of darkness, darkness?
给我打电话，黑暗的含义是什么？你不能通过！
Tel/ me, Whafs the meaning of darkness, darkness? You're not getting though!
没有出路，让我告诉你
N0 way out, let me tell you
0小时！哦给我带路，哦不可能，不可能我们的什么？！
0h! Oh! Show me the way, 0h no way, no way our What?!
0小时！哦给我带路，0h不可能，不可能我们的
0h! Oh! Show me the way, 0h no way, no way our
陛下！
Your Majesty!
他们不会的！
They wouldn't!
不可能。
No way.
他们在大气层中使用了反作用弹头？
They used React/on warheads in-etmosphere?
这些人都疯了！
These people are crazy!
Sigur Berrentz家倒闭了。。。
The Sigur Berrentzs is down...
没事的。
It'll be okay.
约翰神父，所有人都在里面。
Father Johann, everyone's safely inside.
啊！约翰神父。。。
Ugh! Father Johann...
|是吗？！
|S that it?!
海亚特！
Hayate!
没有了！
No more!
/我的声音沾满了鲜血，我鼓起勇气大声喊道
/n a voice tainted with blood, I mustered my strength and shouted out
l/Wpe驱走n/ghz的黑暗！
l/Wpe away the darkness of the n/ghz'!
L/Wpe远离n/ghz的黑暗！警报器的生物折叠波发射
L/Wpe away the darkness of the n/ghz'! Siren's Bio-Fold Wave emission
警报器的生物折叠波发射
Siren's Bio-Fold Wave emission
苦涩的后方是溪流/火星，警报器的生物折叠波发射
Bitter rears are stream/mars, Siren's Bio-Fold Wave emission
苦涩的后方是溪流/火星，
Bitter rears are stream/mars,
苦涩的后腿是溪流/火星，已经下降到18%。
Bitter rears are stream/mars, has dropped to 18%.
即将闪耀光芒
About to sparkle and shine
即将闪耀光芒作为对Wa|kiJre歌曲的回应，
about to sparkle and shine In reaction to Wa|kiJre's song,
照亮我的路，他们站在我这边，似乎已经进入了深度学习模式。
Lighting my way, they're on my side it seems to have entered deep learning mode.
照亮我的路，他们在我身边
Lighting my way, they're on my side
照亮我的路，他们站在我这边。同样，我们已经控制了大部分目标区域。
Lighting my way, they're on my side Just as well, we've seized control of most of the targeted area.
好好研究他们，了解他们的特点。
Study them well and learn their traits.
苦难仍在继续。好好研究他们，了解他们的特点。
Misery ongoing. Study them well and learn their traits.
苦难仍在继续。
Misery ongoing.
L2'仍然痛得要命
L2' still hurts like hell
l2'仍然痛得要命-他们的动作停止了！-现在
l2' still hurts like hell - Their movement's off! - Now!
我相信你，虹膜预先决定了（在那里，做了！）
I believe in you, iris predetermined (been there, done that!)
我相信你，虹膜预先决定了（在那里，做了！）他们已经康复了！
I believe in you, iris predetermined (been there, done that!) They've recovered!
我相信你，虹膜预先决定了（在那里，做了！）
I believe in you, iris predetermined (been there, done that!)
在l/m/z'上方，破折号表示i2'。脉搏跳动。
Over the l/m/z', dash for i2'. Pulse thumping.
越过极限，冲向它。脉搏跳动。不能再这样下去了……有东西来了吗？
O ver the limit, dash for it'. Pulse thumping. Can't keep this up... Something's incoming?
在l/m/z'上方，破折号表示i2'。脉搏跳动。
Over the l/m/z', dash for i2'. Pulse thumping.
G0超出消失点
G0 beyond the vanishing point
G0超出消失点加固？！
G0 beyond the vanishing point Reinforcements?!
这个重开的伤口
The! reopened wound The Macross Gigasion from
这个重新开放的伤口
The! reopened wound
这个重新开放伤口Xaos Listania Branch？它在这里做什么？
The! reopened wound Xaos Listania Branch? What's it doing here?
Xaos Listania分行？它在这里做什么？
Xaos Listania Branch? What's it doing here?
看起来像野兽Xaos Listania Branch？它在这里做什么？
Iooks like a beast Xaos Listania Branch? What's it doing here?
看起来像野兽
Iooks like a beast
那么大的一个sh/p怎么样。。。
How's a sh/p that size...
那种飞行风格，是……吗。。。？
That flying style, is that...?
给所有战斗机加油。
G/jgas/on to all fighters.
立即从w/ndermere登机，与他/她见面。
Get aboard for immediate w/thdra wa/ from W/ndermere.
但是
But...
Wa/kdre已经被提取出来了，快！
Wa/kdre are already being extracted Move it!
收到。
Copy that.
你能跟上吗，博格中尉？
Think you can keep up, Lt. Bogue?
多少加仑/升
What' gal/l
嘿，我很抱歉…我们要退出了！
Heh, my apologies... We're pulling out!
开始/和/ng。那些受损的人先去。
Commence /and/ng. Those hea vi/y damaged go first.
对不起/
Sorry/
哦，不，你不要！
Oh no you don 't!
不好！
Notgood!
/“//获取”Wa/kdre！
/'// get' Wa/kdre!
谢谢
Thanks!
海亚特！
Hayate!
你没事吧？海亚特！海亚特！
You okay? Hayate! Hayate!
是 啊以某种方式
Yeah. Somehow...
Heinz Nehr/ch l/indermere国王，我们特此通知您
King Heinz Nehr/ch l/l/indermere, we hereby inform you that
德温特现在在我们的控制之下。
Derwent is now under our control.
/如果您希望避免进一步的民事/意外伤亡，
/f you wish to avoid further civil/an casualties,
你会立刻投降的。
you will surrender at once.
这怎么样？你在别的地方感到疼痛吗？
How's this? Do you feel pain anywhere else?
没有，但我感觉不到我的腿。。。
No, but I can't feel my legs...
袭击太突然了，我的人。。。
The attack was so sudden, my men...
不要放弃希望，他们可能就在另一个房间里。
Don't give up hope, they might just be in another room.
给我拿治疗Windermerians的数据！
Get me the data on treating Windermerians!
还有多少人受伤？！
How many more wounded are there?!
拉格纳三角洲第三战斗机联队报告，长官。
Delta Flight of Ragna 3rd Fighter Wing reporting sir.
队长，我们感谢你的救援。
Captain, we thank you for the rescue.
你能向我们介绍一下目前的情况吗。。。
Can you brief us on the current situation...
他一定是这艘船的Zentradi档案管理员。
He must be this ship's Zentradi archivist.
隐马尔可夫模型？
Hmm?
埃克塞多尔·福尔莫参谋长。。。
Staff Officer Exedol Folmo...
已经有一段时间了，幻影。
It's been a while, Mirage.
如果你在这里，那意味着。。。
If you're here, that means...
我看你的盲点还很大，幻影中尉。
I see you're still leaving your blind spot wide open, Lt. Mirage.
那是。。。
That's...
我是马克西米利安·杰尼乌斯，麦克罗斯·吉加森的队长。
I'm Maximilian Jenius, captain of the Macross Gigasion.
我想一定是你，爷爷。
I thought it must be you, grandfather.
祖父
Grandfather?
传奇天才飞行员。
The legendary genius ace pilot.
以及Macross 7舰队第七战的队长。
And captain of Battle 7 of the Macross 7 Fleet.
哇！
Whoa!
我听说你退役了，爷爷。你在这里干什么？
I heard you retired from the military, Grandfather. What are you doing here?
我被Xaos招募。
I was recruited by Xaos.
救援命令来自M女士。
Rescue orders came from Lady M.
与总部的沟通还没有结束吗？
Aren't communications with HQ still out?
命令直接传送到我的大脑。
The order was transmitted directly to my brain.
M女士的联络官
Lady M's Fold comms officer
我有相同的DNA，所以。。。
and I are of the same DNA, so...
拉格纳也落入了敌人手中。
Ragna has also fallen to the enemy.
上尉，医务室报告说
Captain, med bay is reporting that
被带上船的温德米尔人情况危急。。。
the Windermerian taken aboard is in critical condition...
约翰神父！
Father Johann!
显然，他希望与Hayate lmmelmann少尉通话。
Apparently he wishes to speak with Lt. Hayate lmmelmann.
我
Me?
你是赖特的。。。
You are Wright's...
赖特|我|曼的儿子，是吗？
Wright |mme|mann's boy, yes?
你的风和他的风相连，我能感觉到。
Your wind is connected to his, I can feel it.
充满对自由和世界的爱的风。
A wind full of love for freedom and for the world.
你怎么知道我爸爸的？
How do you know about my dad?
你的吊坠。是我把它寄给你妈妈的。
Your pendant. I was the one who sent it to your mother.
你但为什么？
You? But why?
嗯，你父亲驻扎在温德米尔。
Well, your father was stationed on Windermere.
呵呵。。。？
Huh...?
莱特·勒梅尔曼少校是一名特工，
Major Wright lmmelmann was a special operative,
他的任务是调查寺庙和史前文化遗址。
his mission was to investigate temples and Protoculture ruins.
特工？我爸爸？
A special operative? My dad?
不要担心。
Worry not.
他从未做过任何伤害我们人民的事。
He never did anything to harm our people.
在他的葬礼上，有人从一座W/ndermer/寺庙里拿走了一些东西。
During his m/ss/on, something was taken from a W/ndermer/an temple.
这是史前文化的遗迹。。。
It was a relic of the Protoculture...
明星歌手的细胞样本。
Cell samples of the Singers of the Stars.
那一定是Mikumo的。。。
That must be Mikumo's...
抓走他们的罪犯是联合国政府。
The culprit who took them was a U.N. Government d/p/omaz'.
他和我们一样是个真正的特工。
He was real/y an operative as we//.
Wright请rne帮忙取回样本。。。
Wright asked rne to help retrieve the samples...
我们只能找到其中一个。
We were able to recover only one of them.
随后，温德米尔与联合国政府的关系恶化，
Then relations between Windermere and the U.N. Government soured,
无法退回样品。
making it impossible to return the sample.
进入女士M。。。
Enter Lady M...
我从没想过赖特少校会参与《明星歌手》。
I never imagined Major Wright was involved with the Singer of the Stars.
他去寻找另一个样本，这让他付出了生命。。。
He went after the other sample, and it cost him his life...
你父亲为温德米尔战斗到最后-
Your father fought for Windermere to the very end—
约翰神父！
Father Johann!
没有必要悲伤，
There is no need to be sad,
我只是在履行我的职责。
lam only fulfilling my duty.
赖特曾经说过，所有的风都是一体的。
Wright used to say that all winds will be as one.
我们未能阻止战争，
We failed to prevent the war,
但总有一天。。。
but someday...
弗雷亚。
Freyja.
|-|我在这里！
|-|'m here!
闪耀过亮的符文会缩短人的寿命。
A rune that shines too bright can shorten one's life.
你必须仔细考虑这口井。
You must reflect on this well.
你为什么活着？你唱什么。。。
For what do you live? For what do you sing...
约翰神父。。。
Father Johann...
随风而行，来到风的喷泉。。。
Go with the Wind, to the Fountain of Wind...
海亚特？
Hayate?
风车人与风融为一体
A Windermerian becoming one with the wind
就是我们的时间结束的时候。所以你以前从未见过。。。
is when our time ends. So you've never seen it before...
偷样品的探员
The agent who stole the samples
目前/y在Epsilon工作。
is current/y working for Epsilon.
Epsilon基金会，一家拥有数千家公司的企业集团。
The Epsilon Foundation, a conglomerate with thousands of companies to its name.
我听到过很多关于他们的阴暗谣言。
I've heard plenty of shady rumors about them.
西德尼·亨特。
Sidney Hunt.
L2'似乎他用这个样本在Epsilon给自己买了一个很好的职位。
L2' seems he bought himself a fine posit/on at Epsilon with the sample.
他是我爸爸后面的人。。。
He's the guy behind my dad's...
这个偷了另一位明星歌手的人。。。
This man who stole the other Singer of the Stars'...
我们听到的声音听起来像Mikumo的，但是。。。
That voice we heard sounded like Mikumo's, but...
里面没有灵魂。
There was no soul in it.
它空荡荡的，漆黑得像黑暗本身。
It was empty and pitch black like darkness itself.
一个Yamikumo。
A Yamikumo.
也许它还没有完全成形。
Maybe it's not fully-formed.
他们可能只制造了脑细胞和其他必要的器官。
They might have only made brain cells and other necessary organs.
但我们感觉到的那个歌手呢？
But what about that singer we sensed?
一个虚拟人。。。
A virturoid...
B/o-Fo/d波具有控制情绪的能力
B/o-Fo/d Waves have the power to con ve y mus/o and emotions
通过与折叠石英共振，穿越时空。
through space and time by resonating with Fold Quartz.
很有可能y正在使用
It's very possible that' the y're using
明星歌手的力量增强了他们的能量
the Singer of the Stars' power t0 boost the energy of their
对引擎和折叠武器进行反应。
React/on Engines and Fold weapons.
你是说他们把音乐当作武器？
You mean they're using music as a weapon?
来自温德米尔的视频信息正在银河网络上播放。
A video message from Windermere is being broadcast on the Galaxy Network.
来自温德米尔？
From Windermere?
-把它放在显示器上-是的，先生。
- Put it up on the monitor. -Aye sir.
这是什么？
What's this?
自古以来，人类就发动战争
Since ancient times, humanity has made war
纵观历史，造成了许多死亡和破坏。
throughout history, causing much death ano' destruction a/ong the way.
我们是He/mda/l，
We are He/mda/l,
我们来到这里是为了把人类从生锈的锁链中解放出来。
and we are here to liberate humanity from its rusted chains.
解放
Liberate?
我们的目标是消除联合国政府、PMC、，
Our objective is to rid the galaxy of the U.N. Government, /V.U./V.S., PMCs,
还有一个秘密，M女士。
and the one secret/y pulling all their strings, Lady M.
M女士是一个被联合国G0 vemmehz甩在后面的阴影人物
Lady M is a shadowy figure that has been mah/jou/at/ng the U.N. G0 vemmehz' behind
禁止使用先进技术和秘密统治人类的场景。
the scenes, banning the use of advanced technology and ruling humanity in secret.
Sharon Apple？！
Sharon Apple?!
不可能！
No way!
禁止使用A/。克隆研究、原型技术的限制、，
The ban on A./. and cloning research, the restrictions 0n Protocu/ture technology,
所有这些都是为了加强对先进技术的垄断。
all implemented to enforce their monopoly over advanced technology.
如果这些都是向公众公开的，那么许多悲剧就可以避免，
Man y tragedies c0u/d've been averted if these had been ava//ab/e t0 the public,
W/ndermer/an re volt’就是其中之一。
the W/ndermer/an re volt' being one 0f them.
LM女士使用了Protocu/ture留下的ce/l样本
L! was Lady M who used ce/l samples left behind by the Protocu/ture
创造超维度声音武器M/kumo Guynemer，
to create the Super Dimensional Sound Weapon M/kumo Guynemer,
利用本应被禁止的克隆技术。
utilizing cloning technology that' was supposed to be banned.
这个人。。。
This man...
我们再也不能容忍这种压迫。
We cannot tolerate this oppress/on any /onger.
我们将推翻这些暴君，把银河系带入一个新时代/
We shall overthrow these tyrants and usher the galaxy into a new age./
I//deo分析完成。
I//deo analysis complete.
伊恩·克伦威尔，
Ian Cromwell,
前联合国第七舰队麦克罗斯·阿斯特里亚号舰长。
former captain of the Macross Astrea in N. U. N. S. ' Seventh Fleet.
八年前，他和他的船一起去了M/A。
He went M/A along with his ship eight years ago.
所以，“铁”克伦威尔还活着。
So, "Iron" Cromwell is still alive.
他是扎尔格甘茨战役的英雄，
He was the hero of the Battle of Zalg-gantz,
他征服的地方
where he subdued
只有一艘船的整个无赖Zentradi舰队。
an entire rogue Zentradi fleet with just one ship.
为什么英雄会这样做？
Why would a hero do this?
看起来像是
That looks like
非法的Sharon Apple型量子A.l.系统的高级模型。
an advanced model of the illegal Sharon Apple type quantum A.l. system.
但是，他们肯定已经取代了生物神经芯片
But instead of a bio-neural chip, they must've
用星之歌手的牢房。
used the Singer of the Stars' cells.
这就是他们带走温德米尔和拉格纳的原因，
So that's why they took Windermere and Ragna,
他们想用史前文化遗址作为扩音器。。。
they want to use the Protoculture ruins as amplifiers...
如果他们占领了球状星团的所有废墟，星系将。。。
If they seize all the ruins in the Globular Cluster, the galaxy would...
根据M女士的命令，
By the order of Lady M,
我们将阻止敌人的计划，并收复星际之歌的细胞。
we are to stop the enemy's plan and recover the Singer of the Stars' cells.
我根本无法应付敌人的敏捷。
I wasn't able to handle the enemy's agility at all.
它们会飞吗？
Will they fly?
别担心，我们会把它们修补好的
Don't worry, we'll patch them up real nice
带有备用Kairos零件。
with spare Kairos parts.
我分析了敌人的
I analyzed the enemy's
Bio Fold Wave System在这里的技术团队的帮助下，
Bio-Fold Wave System with the help of the tech team here,
所以我们增加了更多的折叠石英并更新了放大器
so we're adding more Fold Quartz and updating the amplifiers
在你的每一个女武神身上。
on each of your Valkyries.
如果他们能做到，我们没有理由不能。
If they can do it, there's no reason we can't.
折叠石英应能对我们的音乐做出反应，并提升Valkyries的性能。
The Fold Quartz should react to our music and boost the Valkyries' performance.
就好像我们把音乐当作武器一样。。。
As if we're using our music as a weapon...
这不是真的。
That's not true.
他说得对。你的音乐给了我们力量。
He's right. Your music gives us strength.
保护他人的力量。
The strength to protect others.
保护……的音乐。。。
Music that protects...
甜美的米拉米拉！你真可爱！
Sweet Mira-Mira! You're such a cutie!
他们在对我施压！
T-They're pressing against me!
不太近！
Not so close!
-请不要这么近！-你也很可爱，哈亚·哈亚。
- Not so close please! - You're very sweet too, Haya-Haya.
是的，是的，好的。
Yeah yeah, okay.
我想知道Freyja是否没事。。。
I wonder if Freyja's okay...
说实话，看到约翰神父去世，我有点震惊。
To tell the truth, I was a little shocked seeing Father Johann die.
这真的让我们明白了我们是截然不同的种族。
It really drove home the fact that we're very different races.
结晶…现在我想到了，
Crystallization... Now that I think of it,
Freyja也有迹象。。。
Freyja also showed signs...
这一定是史前文化体系的副作用。
That must've just been a side-effect of the Protoculture system.
当系统停止时，它停止了。。。
It stopped when the system did...
是的，我可能想得太多了。
Yes, I'm probably overthinking things.
现在，即使你也必须意识到这一点。
Now even you must realize it.
我们与地球人不同。
We're different than the Earthlings.
那是。。。
That's...
我们的位置就在那风里。
Our place is within that Wind.
无论花费多少，我都会收回温德米尔。
I will take back Windermere, no matter the cost.
L似乎“克伦威尔在很多场合，
L! seems that' Cromwell has, on many occasions,
请求政府取消对禁用技术的禁令。
petitioned the government t0 /ift the ban on forbidden technology.
他的论点是，使用无人驾驶飞机可以减少人员伤亡，
His argument was that the use of unmanned drones could reduce human casualties,
而控制论和克隆技术可以使在战斗中受伤的士兵受益。
while cybernetic and cloning technology could benefit soldiers injured in battle.
然后，在瓦格宁战役中，他建议使用MDE弹头
Then, during the Battle of Wagenin, he recommended using MDE warheads
阻止强大敌人的入侵。他被忽视了。
to halt an invasion by a powerful enemy. He was ignored.
结果，他的舰队和他的家乡星球都被摧毁了。
As a result, his fleet and his home planet were wiped out.
像他这样的人，幸存了下来。。。
A man like him, having survived something like that...
他已经没有什么可失去的了。
He's got nothing left to lose.
没有什么比受伤的野兽更危险的了。
There's nothing so dangerous as a wounded beast.
这个Heimdall小组怎么样？
What about this Heimdall group?
我以前听说过。人们对秘密行动的M女士感到不满。
I've heard of it before. People displeased with Lady M, who operate in secret.
N、 美国还没有决定如何应对这些问题。
N.U.N.S. still hasn't decided what to do about them yet.
接近目的地。
Approaching destination.
我们的临时运营基地。
Our makeshift base 0f operations.
我懂了。一颗退役的Zentradi工厂卫星。。。
I see. A decommissioned Zentradi factory satellite...
N、 美国救援船？
N.U.N.S. rescue craft?
与这些新敌机相撞的舰队中的幸存者。
Survivors from a fleet that ran into those new enemy fighters.
我是Bogue Con Vaart中尉。我帮你个忙，加入达美航空。
Lt. Bogue Con-Vaart here. I'm doing you a favor and joining Delta Flight.
我会告诉你我不经常做这种服务。
I'll have you know that I don't do this kind of service often.
这是真的，先生？
This for real sir?
这是真的。
It's for real.
现在，让我们开始吧。
Now, let's get started.
112131415161718'
测试“开玩笑”
Quiz' joking around
-$z'0p它-$er/0us/y
-$z'0p it -$er/0us/y
-没有了-Gez迷路了
-No more -Gez' lost
别把我当傻瓜看待
Don't treat me like /'m stupid
哇！
Wow
你是个说话的人
You're one to talk
混蛋，你这个混蛋
Thar son of a bitch, you son of a bitch
你已经走了
Just go away already
你这个偷梦的流氓
You dream-stealing rogue
哇！
Wow
嘿，小姐，那些家伙是披着害羞衣服的狼
Hey Miss, those guys are wolves in sheepis clothing
他们在等着，他们的开关被锁住了。然后他们向你扑来
They're /y/ng in wait, their s/jghts locked on. Then they swoop in on you
这些受骗的家伙一点也不羞耻
These deluded foo/s have no shame
这些欺骗的foo/s毫无羞耻感，敌人的战斗数据上传到了超级幽灵无人机。
These deluded foo/s have no shame Enemy combat data uploaded to Super Ghost drones.
这些受骗的家伙一点也不羞耻
These deluded foo/s have no shame
这些被欺骗的foo/s没有羞耻感，减少了60%的限制器。
These deluded foo/s have no shame Reducing limiter by 60%.
这些受骗的家伙一点也不羞耻
These deluded foo/s have no shame
他们甚至不了解心痛
They don't even understand heartache
他们甚至都不明白心痛Sl/jopery SUNOF/
They don't even understand heartache Sl/jopery sunofa. . . ./
Sl/jopery太阳神/
Sl/jopery sunofa. . . ./
你喜欢什么类型的女孩？（你这个傻瓜）Sl/jopery sunof/
Your type of girl? (you fool) Sl/jopery sunofa. . . ./
你喜欢什么类型的女孩？（你这个傻瓜）
Your type of girl? (you fool)
你喜欢什么类型的女孩？（你这个傻瓜）该死，什么都打不中！
Your type of girl? (you fool) Dammit', can 't hit a thing!
该死，什么都打不中！
Dammit', can 't hit a thing!
别“2”让我笑了妈的，什么都打不中！
Don '2' make me laugh Dammit', can 't hit a thing!
不要让我发笑
Don '2' make me laugh
别逗我笑他们很快！
Don '2' make me laugh They're fast!
他们很快！
They're fast!
见7（见9）他们很快！
See 7 (See .9) They're fast!
海($667)
Sea? ($667)
一个不好的douohebag，
A no good douohebag,
就像他们说的那样
just like they say
就像他们说的好吧，女孩们，加油！
just like they say Alright girls, hit it!
就像他们说的那样
Just like they say
S0。。。
S0...
来吧，女人们，大声点，大声点
Come on women, raise your voices, make some noise
这个世界上只有一个真理
There's only one truth in this world
看看吧
Take a look
马德尼丝的纯洁是如此迷人，
A ma/denis purity is so bewitch/ng,
它会让你兴奋不已，让你目瞪口呆
it'll thrill you and leave you staggering
这会让你兴奋不已，让你惊愕不已谢谢，幻影！
it'll thrill you and leave you staggering Thanks, Mirage!
它会让你兴奋不已，让你目瞪口呆
It'll thrill you and leave you staggering
这会让你兴奋不已，让你惊愕不已。别谢我，我们走吧/
it'll thrill you and leave you staggering Don't thank me, let's g0./
/z“//永远不会
/z"// never ever
代表这个
stand for this
我不会让任何人说一切都毁了
I won't let anyone say that everyth/ngis ruined
我不在乎一切是否一团糟
I don't care if everything gets messed up
测试“开玩笑”
Quiz' joking around
-$z'0p它-$er/0us/y
-$z'0p it -$er/0us/y
-没有了-Gez迷路了
-No more -Gez' lost
别把我当傻瓜看待
Stop treating me like /'m stupid
哇，我们做到了。。。
Wow We did it...
哇！
Wow
哇，不是真的。这些不能与真实的东西相比。
Wow Not really. These don't compare to the real thing.
不是真的。这些不能与真实的东西相比。
Not really. These don't compare to the real thing.
精确/y！
Precise/y!
一辆YF-29？为什么这里有一个蓝色的Durandal？
A YF-29? Why's there a blue Durandal out here?
不可能！
It can't be!
我来了！
Here I come!
一个单人间
A single
单曲哇！
A single Whoa!
哇！
Whoa!
（单身）哇！
(single) Whoa!
（唱/唱）
(sing/e)
声音很小
Voice is small
声音太小了这太糟糕了，我们必须齐声歌唱！
voice is small This is bad, we have to sing as one!
这太糟糕了，我们必须齐声歌唱！
This is bad, we have to sing as one!
所以它可以扼杀我们这太糟糕了，我们必须齐声歌唱！
So it can be snuffed our This is bad, we have to sing as one!
所以它可以被我们的
So it can be snuffed our
这样我们的副本就可以被扼杀了！
so it can be snuffed our Copy!
所以它可以被我们的
So it can be snuffed our
这样就可以扼杀我们的嘎！多大的风啊！但是
so it can be snuffed our Gah! What a Wind! But...!
所以它可以被我们的
So it can be snuffed our
日分！如果我们能超越时间（跨越海洋）
Bu! if we can verge beyond time (across the sea)
整个（整个）深红骑士！
The entire (entire) Crimson Knight!
整个（整体）
The entire (entire)
将来
Future
未来远离我的路！
future Outta my way!
将来
Future
未来你离开我的！
future You get outta mine!
你离开我的！
You get outta mine!
是我们的，你离开我的！
Is ours You get outta mine!
是我们的吗
Is ours
我们的Delta 5和6'，你在干什么？！
is ours Delta 5 and 6', what are you doing?!
是我们的吗
Is ours
S0。。。
S0...
S0…我跟不上他们。。。
S0... I can't keep up with them...
我跟不上他们。。。
I can't keep up with them...
来吧，女人们，提高嗓门，制造一些噪音，我跟不上他们。。。
Come on women, raise your voices, make some noise I can't keep up with them...
来吧，女人们，大声点，大声点
Come on women, raise your voices, make some noise
这个世界上只有一个真理
There's only one truth in this world
看看吧
Take a look
看看啊！
Take a look Ah!
看看吧
Take a look
马德尼丝的纯洁是如此迷人，
A ma/denis purity is so bewitch/ng,
马德尼的纯洁是如此迷人，这到底是什么？
A ma/denis purity is so bewitch/ng, What the hell is this?
这到底是什么？
What the hell is this?
这会让你兴奋不已，让你目瞪口呆这到底是什么？
It'll thrill you and leave you staggering What the hell is this?
它会让你兴奋不已，让你目瞪口呆
It'll thrill you and leave you staggering
这会让你兴奋不已，让你惊愕不已。他不像梅瑟或白骑士。
it'll thrill you and leave you staggering He's not like Messer or the White Knight.
它会让你兴奋不已，让你目瞪口呆
It'll thrill you and leave you staggering
这会让你兴奋不已，让你目瞪口呆我根本看不懂他！
it'll thrill you and leave you staggering I can't read him at all!
我根本看不懂他！
I can't read him at all!
/z“//我从来没有读过他！
/z"// never ever I can't read him at all!
/z“//永远不会
/z"// never ever
代表这个
stand for this
代表这个啊，臭名昭著的lmmelmann舞蹈。
stand for this Ah, the notorious lmmelmann Dance.
啊，臭名昭著的lmmelmann舞蹈。
Ah, the notorious lmmelmann Dance.
我不会让任何人说一切都毁了啊，臭名昭著的lmmelmann舞蹈。
I won't let anyone say that everyth/ngis ruined Ah, the notorious lmmelmann Dance.
我不会让任何人说一切都毁了
I won't let anyone say that everyth/ngis ruined
我不会让任何人说一切都毁了他很有天赋，但是。。。！
I won't let anyone say that everyth/ngis ruined He's got talent, but...!
我不在乎一切是否一团糟
I don't care if everything gets messed up
测试“开玩笑”
Quiz' joking around
-$z'0p它-$er/0us/y
-$z'0p it -$er/0us/y
-没有了-Gez迷路了
-No more -Gez' lost
别把我当傻瓜看待
Don't treat me like /'m stupid
哇！
Wow
你是个说话的人
You're one to talk
混蛋，你这个混蛋
Thar son of a bitch, you son of a bitch
你已经走了
Just go away already
你这个偷梦的流氓
You dream-stealing rogue
哇！
Wow
我想我会称之为不可思议的舞蹈。
Think I'll call that the Incredible Dance.
伙计，我们被打败了。
Man, we got beat.
你飞得像只讨厌的昆虫。
You fly like a pesky insect.
那是什么？
What's that?
我的使命是解放温德米尔，
I'm on a mission to liberate Windermere,
所以别再妨碍我了！
so don't get in my way again!
我也是！
So am I!
为了你的女孩？这不是游戏。
For your girl? This isn't a game.
你说什么？
What did you say?
哇哦。拜托，伙计，别这样。
Whoa. C'mon man, don't.
Chuck的家人在Ragna。。。
Chuck's family's on Ragna...
Freyja的村庄在温德米尔！
and Freyja's village is on Windermere!
你在乎什么？你来自地球。
What do you care? You're from Earth.
他们现在是我生活的重要组成部分！
They're an important part of my life now!
所以我要夺回拉格纳和温德米尔！
So I'm going to take back Ragna and Windermere!
你们都在说话！
You're all talk!
你把他们弄回来后打算做什么？！你们这些该死的入侵者！
What do you plan on doing after you get them back?! You damn invaders!
立刻停止！
Stop this at once!
博格中尉。
Lt. Bogue.
与Sv-262不同，VF-31的滚动速度会随着您的移动而增加。
Unlike the Sv-262, the roll rate of the VF-31 increases as you go.
尽快练习并习惯。
Practice and get used to that ASAP.
我知道。
I know.
海亚特·勒梅尔曼。
Hayate lmmelmann.
我知道你的感受，但你需要有耐心。
I know how you're feeling, but you need to have patience.
你们两个。我希望你在战场上表现出那样的精神。
You two. I wish you had shown that much spirit on the battlefield.
祖父
Grandfather!
爷爷……队长，你没事吧？
Grandpa... Captain are you alright?
你太善良了，不可能成为一名优秀的拳击手。
You're too kind-hearted to be a good fighter.
你缺乏杀戮的决心
You lack the resolve to go for the kill
完全不顾他人。
with total disregard for others.
据我所知，你可能已经脱离了一场浪漫的竞争。
You've probably even disengaged from a romantic rivalry, for all I know.
T-那是。！
T-That's. . .!
我
I...
我没有你的天赋，队长。
I don't have your genius, captain.
是的，你确实缺乏成为高手的天赋。
Yes, you do lack the talent to be an ace.
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
海亚特？
Hayate?
在这里
Here.
那是……奶奶的苹果！
That's... Grandma's apple!
对不起，我花了这么长时间才把它给你。
Sorry it took me so long to get it to you.
谢谢你，海亚特，谢谢你！
Thank you Hayate, thank you!
它被撞伤了，但里面有种子。
It's pretty bruised up, but there are seeds inside.
我保证我会取回温德米尔，
I promise I'll take back Windermere,
然后我们一起用这些种子重新种植果园，好吗？
then we'll replant the orchard with these seeds together, okay?
即使这需要我们多年……不，几十年。
Even if it takes us years... No, decades.
好吧，弗雷维亚？
Okay, Frevia'?
是的…当然。
Y-Yes... Sure.
非常感谢。
Thank you.
弗雷亚？
Freyja?
啊，我得走了。
Ah, I have to go.
嗯？嘿，弗雷维亚？
Huh? Hey, Frevia'?
你必须原谅海亚特。
You must forgive Hayate.
他是个白痴，但他是好意的。
He's an idiot, but he means well.
是的，我知道。
Yeah, I know.
但那就是你爱上的那种人，对吗？
But that's the kind of guy you fell in love with, right?
是的，但是……我现在看到我不同了，
Yes but... I see now that I'm different,
而不是你和海亚特。
than you and Hayate.
所以你认为海亚特和你在一起会不高兴吗？
So you think Hayate won't be happy if he's with you?
你不能自己决定事情！
You can't just decide things on your own!
你们两个必须一起想清楚！
Both of you have to think this through together!
好的）'-
Alright)'-
我也爱上了海亚特。
I was in love with Hayate too.
嗯？
Huh?
但我觉得我对他的感觉和你有点不同。
But I think my feelings for him were a little bit different than yours.
我想我很钦佩他。
I guess I admired him.
我想成为一个像他一样自由的人。
I wanted to be a free spirit like him.
我支持你们俩。
I'm rooting for you both.
幻景
Mirage...
如今，星际婚姻已不再罕见。
And inter-planetary marriages are no longer a rare thing these days.
哦，对了，马基纳告诉我。
Oh right, Makina told me.
麦克斯队长是第一个这样做的人！
Captain Max was the first one to do it!
我的祖父母不是一个好榜样！
M-My grandparents are not a good example!
被小报评为最有可能分手的名人夫妇
Voted No.1 famous couple most likely to split by the tabloids
连续50年。
for 5O years in a row.
公平地说，文章说
To be fair, the articles said
他们的问题与其说是性格问题，不如说是其他问题。
their problem was more their personalities than anything else.
谈恋爱？我们也想混在一起！
Talking romance? We wanna be in the mix too!
混合和搅拌。小心，不要混合。
Mixing and churning. Caution, do not mix.
来吧，不要再这样了！
Come on, not again!
我想我明白了
I thought I understood
我们的种族有多不同，但是。。。
how different our races were, but...
但这并没有改变你对她的感觉，对吧？
But that doesn't change how you feel about her right?
没有，但是…我想，
No but... I got to thinking,
和我在一起她真的会开心吗？
would she really be happy being with me?
你们两个需要好好谈谈。
You two need to talk this through.
如果你等到为时已晚，你会后悔的。
If you wait until it's too late, you'll regret it.
卡奈姆。。。
Kaname...
如果你半途而废，
If you half-ass this thing,
你要处理好所有的WalkUre。知道了？
you'll have all of WalkUre to deal with. Got it?
是的，女士。
Yes ma'am.
你知道，我从来都不想当船长。
I never wanted to be ship's captain you know.
当时，联合国缺少军官，
At the time, N.U.N.S. was short on officers,
所以我别无选择，只能接受。
so I had no choice but to accept.
但即使是现在，我仍然觉得我生来就是一名飞行员，而不是别的什么。
But even now, I still feel I was born to be a pilot and nothing else.
不过，对于幻影恐怕不能这么说。
I'm afraid the same can't be said for Mirage though.
是的，她并不是真正优秀的飞行员材料。
Yes, she's not really ace pilot material.
熄火气体？
Knockout gas?
你在那里干什么！
What are you doing there!
使沮丧
Get down!
阿拉德！
Arad!
阿拉德指挥官，你没事吧？
Commander Arad, are you alright?
我们的位置被泄露了。。。
Our location's been compromised...
恐怕比那更糟。
I'm afraid it's worse than that.
我道歉。我不在车站的时候。。。
My apologies. I was away from my station when...
不，没关系。
No, it's alright.
我将把团队交给你，幻影。
I'm leaving the team in your charge, Mirage.
罗杰。
Roger.
乐谱？
A musical score?
这是M女士的指示。
It's a directive from Lady M.
仅为Xaos的眼睛编码？
Encoded for Xaos' eyes only?
那东西窃取了信息，所以。。。
That thing hacked the message, so...
通过分析加密数据，
By analyzing the encrypted data,
我们的敌人一定知道他们能找到M女士的位置。
our enemy must've figured that they can pinpoint Lady M's location.
麦克斯队长，
Captain Max,
我想你知道M女士的真实身份吧？
I assume you know Lady M's true identity?
他们的官方代号是Lady Megaroad-O1。
Their official codename is Lady Megaroad-O1.
Megaroad-O 1…你是说。。。？
Megaroad-O 1... You mean...?
2012年离开地球的第一批移民舰队的旗舰舰。
The flagship of the First Emigration Fleet that left Earth in 2012.
通信在2016年丢失，从那以后就一直丢失。。。
Comms were lost in 2016, and they've been missing ever since...
然后是我们的一个附属组织
Then one of our affiliate organizations
接收到来自子空间的折叠波传输
picked up a Fold Wave transmission coming from subspace
使用与Megaroad-O1相同的频率。
using the same frequency as the Megaroad-O1.
分析变速器后，
After analyzing the transmission,
我们发现它包含了
we found that it contained the protocol codes needed to
解开星歌和史前文化遗址的神秘面纱。
unlock the mystery of the Star Song and the Protoculture ruins.
那么M女士就是Megar0ad-077上的人
Then Lady M is someone aboard the Megar0ad-077
我们不知道。
We don't know.
我们甚至不确定是否可以称它们为智能生命体。
We're unsure if we can even call them an intelligent lifeform.
安娜，你相信这样的事吗？
Ana' you trusted such a thing?
至少他们不是我们的敌人。
They're not our enemy, at least.
目前为止。
For now.
你不知道。
You don't know that.
如果你问我，这位女士M和克伦威尔没什么不同。
If you ask me, this Lady M's not so different from Cromwell.
这个星系的类人物种
The humanoid spec/es 0f this galaxy
他们还太年轻，无法处理协议的关系。
are still too adolescent t0 handle the rel/cs of the Protocu/ture.
/似乎M女士在守护着文明，等待它成熟。
/t would seem that Lady M watches over civilization, waiting for it t0 mature.
我们不会犯50万年前古希腊所犯的错误。
S0 we do not make the same mistakes the Protocu/ture made 500, 000 years ago.
我们通知他们了吗？
Have we alerted them?
是的，但Megaroad Ot在褶皱断层之间漂浮
Yes, but the Megaroad-Ot is caught adrift between Fold Faults
其系统为cr/jop/ea’。
with its systems cr/jop/ea'.
逃跑是不可能的。
Escape is impossible.
不
No...
你是认真的吗？也许吧，妈妈/
Are you serious? Maybe, ma ybe...0h/
让它成为现实
Just make it a reality
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say?
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？F/y/With/0ve的（lovefis）
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say? F/y/ With /0ve's (lovefis)
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say?
0美元疯狂，疯狂，得到我们的！你怎么说？亲吻（Kiss）
$0 crazy, crazy, get our! What do you say? Kiss (kiss)
亲吻（Kiss）
Kiss (kiss)
我知道你想要什么吻
I know what you want Kiss (kiss)
我知道你想要什么
I know what you want
我知道你想要什么让我们联系到时间的尽头
I know what you want Let's link to the end of time
让我们链接到时间的末尾
Let's link to the end of time
你是唯一的一个，带我去看看。让我们链接到时间的尽头
You 're the only one, take me h/jgher Let's link to the end of time
你是唯一的，带我去吧
You 're the only one, take me h/jgher
你是唯一的，带我去爱你
You 're the only one, take me h/jgher / love you
你是唯一的，带我去吧
You 're the only one, take me h/jgher
你是唯一一个，带我去打破通行限制。。。
You 're the only one, take me h/jgher Breaking the limits ofpass/on...
打破通行限制。。。
Breaking the limits ofpass/on...
绝对零度
Absolute zero with you
绝对零和你的敌人生物折叠波歌曲中立。
Absolute zero with you Enemy Bio-Fold Wave Song neutralized.
（哈哈~）高级折叠扩音器正在工作！
(Hah ~) Advanced Fold Sound Amplifiers are working!
三角洲4号，你有一个鬼魂中队七点过来！
Delta 4, you've got a squadron of Ghosts coming in at seven o'clock!
复制
Copy!
三角洲5号，把你的注意力集中在接近的强盗身上。
Delta 5, keep your focus solely on the approaching bandits.
G01“它！
G01' it!
三角洲3号，掩护三角洲5号的6号！
Delta 3, cover Delta 5's six!
/“//点燃你的梦想三角洲3号，覆盖三角洲5号的6号！
/'// kindle your dreams Delta 3, cover Delta 5's six!
拥抱一个//你相信的Oorah先生！
Embrace a// that you believe Oorah sir!
拥抱你相信的
Embrace a// that you believe
拥抱一个//你相信的三角洲6号，强盗三点钟高！
Embrace a// that you believe Delta 6, bandits three o'clock high!
拥抱你相信的
Embrace a// that you believe
拥抱你相信的Da/
Embrace a// that you believe Da./
鲁莽的基因
Reckless genes
几乎是一个谎言，心软到了爱的地步
Almost a lie, heart enf/amed to the point of loving
抖掉i2'
Shake i2' off
到另一个维度，挤压我
to another dimension, squeeze me
狠狠地打，
Beating hard,
核心即将崩溃（看着我）
Cores about to crash (watch me)
爱自然的你
Loving the natural you
-眼泪-z'haz'可以'！被抛弃
- Tears -z'haz' can'! be shed
-a/0ne连接
-a/0ne connect
-我们的命运
-our destinies
F/y/Live（着迷/y）
F/y/ Live (infatuated/y)
爱的速度
A1' the speed (of love)
Super N0变量
Sup er N0 va tic
Hav/ng失去了我的翅膀，Super N0 vatic
Ha v/ng lost my wings, Sup er N0 va tic
他失去了我的翅膀，
Ha v/ng lost my wings,
I fa/l公司
I fa/l
/'是免费的
/'m free
/自由了他们加速了？！
/'m free They accelerated?!
他们加速了？！
They accelerated?!
他们终于加速了？！
At last They accelerated?!
最后
At last
这首歌到底是什么？
at last What the hell is this song?
最后
At last
最后这个邪恶的世界。。。
at last This evil W/no'...
最后
at last
最后是Bio Fold Waves！
at last Bio-Fold Waves!
生物折叠波！
Bio-Fold Waves!
它在倍增吗？！
Is it multiplying?!
现在我通过了，它在倍增吗？！
Now I pass ls it multiplying?!
现在我通过了
Now I pass
现在/通过分析…我们的歌唱。。。
Now / pass Analyzed... our singing...
分析…我们的歌唱。。。
Analyzed... our singing...
判断，分析…我们的歌唱。。。
judgement, Analyzed... our singing...
判断
judgement,
判断，它从我们身上学到了什么？
judgement, It learned from us?
判断
Judgement,
关于se/f-r/ighteous
on a se/f-r/ghteous
等等，这是。。。！
on a se/f-r/ghteous Wait, this is...!
关于se/f-r/ightous
On a se/f-r/ghteous
问题00’
Q00'
音乐之神是Euphoria。
god Music is Euphoria.
问题00’
Q00'
上帝音乐是绝望。
god Music is Despair.
问题00’
Q00'
音乐是欲望。
god Music is Desire.
音乐是疯狂的。
Music is Insanity.
音乐是黑暗。
Music is Darkness.
在堕落天使的歌声中死去。
Die, by the songs of fallen angels.
超级黑暗天使，Yami_Q_ray！
Super Dark Angels, Yami_Q_ray!
Yami_Q_ray？！
Yami_Q_ray?!
现在娱乐我真的吗？
Now entertain me Seriously?
这个世界太无聊了，
This world is so boring,
/我太失望了
/'m so disillusioned
/“//夺走你的一切
/'// take everything from you
你的爱，
A// your love,
梦想，
dreams,
音乐
music,
和希望
and hope
没有人会听到你
N0 one will hear you
N0 one将听到您100%的功率输出。
N0 one will hear you Power output at 100%.
来吧，打破它，警报器系统已经唤醒。
Come on, break it The Siren System has awakened.
来吧，打破它
Come on, break it
来吧，打破它。就这样。
Come on, break it So it's done.
来吧，打破它
Come on, break it
成件。你的身体，
Into lift/e pieces. Your body,
你的生命，你的一切
your life, your all
你的生活，你所有的史前文化结构都出现了
your life, your all Protoculture structures have appeared
你的生命，你的一切
your life, your all
你的生命，你在文德米尔和拉格纳的一切！
your life, your all on both Windermere and Ragna!
在温德米尔和拉格纳！
On both Windermere and Ragna!
/我对温德米尔和拉格纳的感情很感兴趣！
/'m n02' interested in feelings, on both Windermere and Ragna!
/“我n02”对感情感兴趣，
/'m n02' interested in feelings,
/我对感觉感兴趣，什么？！
/'m n02' interested in feelings, What?!
/“我n02”对感情感兴趣，
/'m n02' interested in feelings,
/'mn02'对感情感兴趣，他们也出现在沃尔多和阿尔海姆身上！
/'m n02' interested in feelings, They've appeared on Voldor and Alfheim as well!
他们也出现在沃尔多和阿尔海姆身上！
They've appeared on Voldor and Alfheim as well!
/他们也出现在沃尔多和阿尔海姆身上！
/'// wreck i2' all They've appeared on Voldor and Alfheim as well!
/'//破坏i2'全部
/'// wreck i2' all
/“//残骸i2”所有超级折叠门开始形成。
/'// wreck i2' all A Super Fold Gate is starting to form.
/'//破坏i2'全部
/'// wreck i2' all
/他们用深度学习
/'// wreck i2' all They used deep learning to
他们利用深度学习
They used deep learning to
Iris开始了-Desz’r0y-结束的声音他们用深入的学习
Iris begun -Desz'r0y- The sound of the end They used deep learning to
Iris开始-Desz’r0y-结束的声音
Iris begun -Desz'r0y- The sound of the end
Iris开始-Desz’r0y-结尾的声音复制了《黑暗歌手》，
Iris begun -Desz'r0y- The sound of the end create copies of the Singer of the Dark,
Iris开始-Desz’r0y-结束的声音
Iris begun -Desz'r0y- The sound of the end
艾丽斯开始了——德斯的歌——结尾的声音增强了他们的歌唱能力。
Iris begun -Desz'r0y- The sound of the end amplifying their singing power.
增强他们的歌唱能力。
Amplifying their singing power.
已经响起，不要妨碍我扩大他们的歌唱能力。
Has rung out, don't get in my way amplifying their singing power.
已经挂断电话了，别挡我的路
Has rung out, don't get in my way
打来电话，别挡我的路，他们来了！所有单位，近距离作战！
has rung out, don't get in my way Here they come! All units, engage at close range!
像天使一样，从你的D.A/.A深处
Like an Angel, from the depths of your D.A/.A
唱毁灭之歌，就像你在尖叫
Sing devastation, like you're screaming
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。邪恶呼呼声被打破了！
Evil. Evil. You too are evil. Evil The hul/'s been breached!
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。恶毒的
Evil. Evil. You too are evil. Evil
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。邪恶该死！
Evil. Evil. You too are evil. Evil Shit'!
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。恶毒的
Evil. Evil. You too are evil. Evil
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。邪恶的追逐！
Evil. Evil. You too are evil. Evil Giving chase!
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。恶毒的
Evil. Evil. You too are evil. Evil
在内心深处，你一定也希望如此
Deep inside, you must be wishing it too
但否认。否认说谎者。你必须/我/
But deny. Deny. Liar. You st/l/
haven'2'似乎已经够痛了
haven '2' had enough pain, it seems
haven'2'已经够痛了，看来敌人的战机来了！
haven '2' had enough pain, it seems Enemy fighters inbound!
看来2号已经够痛了
Haven '2' had enough pain, it seems
已经“2”受够了痛苦，似乎不要退缩！破坏者中队，行动起来拦截！
haven '2' had enough pain, it seems Do not fall back! Destroid squadrons, move to intercept!
不要后退！破坏者中队，行动起来拦截！
Do not fall back! Destroid squadrons, move to intercept!
Per/sh/ng是摇头丸
Per/sh/ng is ecstasy
该死！别再胡闹了！
Dammit! Quit buzzing around!
海亚特！
Hayate!
我们再来点吧
Let's p/a y some more
这个/sn'2'接近/y就够了
This /sn '2' near/y enough
这已经够近了他们在骚扰我们！
This /sn '2' near/y enough They're messing with us!
这个/sn'2'接近/y就够了
This /sn '2' near/y enough
很接近，
It's close,
快到了，Freyja！
It's close, Freyja!
星座
The constellation
每30年才来一次
that comes but once every 30 years
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
我不想睡着
I don't want to fal/ asleep
unri/I see i2'with you（我和你在一起）
unri/ I see i2' with you
我感觉到齿轮在转动
I feel the gears turning
慢/y，慢/ow/y什么？！
slow/y, s/ow/y What?!
慢/y，慢/ow/y
Slow/y, s/ow/y
弗雷亚”
Freyia"
你有没有想过有多少秒
Have you ever wondered how many seconds
你有没有想过Fre Fre有多少秒！
Have you ever wondered how many seconds Fre-Fre!
你有没有想过有多少秒
Have you ever wondered how many seconds
你有没有想过有多少秒不Freyja，不要！
Have you ever wondered how many seconds No Freyja, don't!
一年后，
Are in a year,
一天，一刻？
a day, a moment?
现在别摔倒我，我都不想知道
Don't fell me now, I don't even wanna know
下一颗彗星什么时候会来
when the next comet will come
现在不要感觉/我，即使这是结束，
Don't fel/ me now, even if this is the end,
现在不要告诉我，即使这是一个骗局，那是怎么回事？！
Don't te// me now, even if this is the eno', That maneuver, what's going on?!
现在不要感觉/我，即使这是结束，
Don't fel/ me now, even if this is the end,
现在不要感觉/我，即使这是结束，海亚特！
Don't fel/ me now, even if this is the end, Hayate!
现在不要感觉/我，即使这是结束，
Don't fel/ me now, even if this is the end,
我不想后悔
I don't wam' to regret i2'
所有部队，撤离！
All forces, evacuate!
风开始刮了
The wind starts to blow
没有警告
without warning
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
发生了什么？
What's happening?
现在
Now!
别让我失望，ton/gm’
Don't let me down, ton/gm'
/“//找到那个星座
/'// find that constellation
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
Macross Gigasion执行了紧急折叠。
The Macross Gigasion has executed an emergency Fold.
嗯，警报器系统似乎有问题？
Hmm, seems there's an issue with the Siren System?
这不是问题。
It's not a problem.
我们成功地生成了与所有五个成员相同的Bio Fold波
We succeeded in generating Bio-Fold Waves equal to that of all five members
结合一个人的脑细胞计数。
of Walkiire combined with the brain cell count of a single person.
你看，
And look,
我们已经占领了所有有史前文化遗迹的星球。
we've seized all the planets that have Protoculture ruins.
现在我们可以开门了
Now we can open
银河系任何地方的超级折叠门。
Super Fold Gates anywhere in the galaxy.
资助罗伊德·布雷姆的研究确实获得了很好的回报。
Funding Roid Brehm's research has paid off very well indeed.
首先你帮助了温德米尔人，现在你在帮助我们。。。
First you aided the Windermerians, now you're helping us...
真聪明。
How clever.
嗯，你们都是我们的宝贵客户。
Well, you're both our valued customers.
增强感官意识？
Enhanced sensory awareness?
感觉到Hayate有危险，
Sensing Hayate was in danger,
Freyja的生物折叠波增强到最大值。
Freyja's Bio-Fold Waves intensified to the max.
这使得他的折叠石英与Fre Fre的歌声产生共鸣，
This caused his Fold Quartz to resonate with Fre-Fre's singing,
增强哈亚·哈亚的感官和能力。
enhancing Haya-Haya's senses and abilities.
所以这让他发疯了。。。
So it made him go berserk...
这是我的错…她是这样的。
It's my fault... she's like this.
唱歌…是…我的。。。
Singing... is... my...
Freyja，我要带你离开任务。
Freyja, I'm taking you off the mission.
不
No...
一个连自己都站不住的人
Someone who can't even stand on their own
将成为战场上的障碍。
will be a hindrance on the battlefield.
所以你现在就休息一下。
So you just rest for now.
放松点，我们会夺回温德米尔和拉格纳。
Relax, we'll take back Windermere and Ragna.
然后我们将举行一个有水母和苹果的聚会。
Then we'll have a party with jellyfish and apples.
扔出
Chuck...
这里，弗雷弗雷。。。
Here, Fre-Fre...
这是哈亚·哈亚拯救的苹果的种子。
It's a seed from the apple that Haya-Haya saved.
你应该把它带回温德米尔。
You should bring it back to Windermere.
好的）'-
Alright)'-
Freyja再也不会唱歌了？
Freyja can't sing anymore?
你这是什么意思？！
What do you mean by that?!
你看到她变得多么虚弱了。。。
You saw how weak she's become...
她不太可能再承受增强型生物折叠波的压力了。。。
It's unlikely she can take the strain of enhanced Bio-Fold Waves anymore...
她不能治好吗？
Can't she be cured?
结晶……不是一种疾病。
Crystallization... isn't a disease.
她的细胞受损严重。
The damage to her cells is severe.
即使她停下来，损害已经造成。。。
Even if she stops, the damage has been done...
“闪耀过亮的符文会缩短人的生命……”
"A rune that shines too bright can shorten one's |ife..."
这就是约翰神父的意思。
S0 this is what Father Johann meant.
国王陛下也出现了身体变白的情况。
The whitening of the body happened to His Majesty the King as well.
那么，如果她不唱歌，情况不会变得更糟吗？
So, if she doesn't sing, it won't get worse?
我不知道。但她不能在战场上唱歌。。。
I don't know. But she can't sing on battlefield...
Walkijlre只需要你们四个人就可以完成任务。这不容易。。。
Walkijlre will do the mission with just four of you then. It won't be easy...
我们会完成这项工作的。
We'll get the job done.
如果我们能阻止敌人的歌唱。。。
If we can somehow jam the enemy's singing...
让我们马上开始。
Let's get started right away.
可以
Okay.
米库莫？
Mikumo?
一、 …想唱歌。。。！
I... want to sing...!
和Freyja…再次和你，Freyja。。。
With Freyja... With you again, Freyja...
米库莫。。。
Mikumo...
战争期间，当事情变得艰难时，音乐帮助我度过了难关。
When things got rough during the war, music helped get me through it.
这就是为什么我总是尊敬沃尔基Jre。你用音乐保护人们。
That's why I always looked up to WalkiJre. You protect people with music.
别担心。无论发生什么，我都会。。。
Don't worry. No matter what happens, I'll...
永远是步行者，好吗？
always be a Walkilre, okay?
弗雷亚”
Freyia"
已经100多年了，马西米兰总司令。
it's been I00 long, Commander-in-Chief Maximilian.
我们很高兴再次来到你身边。
We 're a// excited to f/jght beside you again.
荣誉属于我。我指望着你。
The honor is mine. I'm counting on you.
阿拉德指挥官，我们的计划是什么？
Commander Arad, what's our plan?
下次敌人打开折叠门时，
The next time the enemy opens their Fold gates,
我们会穿过其中一个袭击温德米尔。
we'll go through one of them and attack Windermere.
这可能吗？
Is that possible?
我们根据阿拉德指挥官的建议制定了一个罢工计划。
We've devised a strike plan based on Commander Arad's proposal.
我们相信，如果我们
We believe it to be possible if we
利用Wa | kiJre的Bio Fold Waves提升我们船的折叠动力。
boost the Fold drives of our ships with Wa|kiJre's Bio-Fold Waves.
我们相信，在任何有史前文化遗迹的星球上，大门都可以打开。
We believe the gates can be opened on any planet with Protoculture ruins.
离我们目前位置最近的是。。。
The nearest one to our current position is...
阿尔海姆星球。
Planet Alfheim.
我们应该能够利用小行星带作为掩护，潜入而不被发现。
We should be able to sneak in undetected by using the asteroid belt as cover.
卡内小姐，有什么不对劲吗？
Is there something wrong, Miss Kaname?
没有，先生。
No sir.
一位倒下的战友在美国北联合国服役时曾驻扎在那个星球上。
A fallen comrade used to be stationed on that planet when he served in N.U.N.S.
Messer lhlefeld少尉。
Lt. Messer lhlefeld.
A//向战斗站投降！重复，a//手到战斗站！
A// hands t0 battle stations! Repeat, a// hands to battle stations!
我向战斗站投降！
A/l hands to battle stations!
我飞行指挥官？
Me? Flight commander?
我不能。我们需要你来领导我们，阿拉德指挥官！
I can't. We need you to lead us, Commander Arad!
从桥上我只能做这么多。
There's only so much I can do from the bridge.
没事的。你可以做到。
It'll be okay. You can do it.
做你自己。在你自己的天空中飞翔。
Just be yourself. Fly in your own sky.
飞…在我自己的天空。。。
Fly... in my own sky...
海亚特。
Hayate.
先生
Sir.
对不起，没有告诉你关于你父亲的事。
Sorry for not telling you about your father.
没关系。但我从没想到他在温德米尔。
It's alright. But I never would've guessed he was on Windermere.
我改天再告诉你更多关于他的事。
I'll tell you more about him some other time.
至少是对孩子友好的故事。
The kid-friendly stories, at least.
是的，请这样做。
Yes, please do.
嗯，你没有地方吗？
Well, don't you have somewhere to be?
嗯？
Huh?
手术前剩下的时间不多了。
Not much time left before the operation.
是的……谢谢你，先生。
Yes... Thank you sir.
弗雷亚”
Freyia"
那个该死的女孩。。。
That darn girl...
必须快点。。。
Gotta hurry...
别傻了！你要试着唱歌吗？！在你的情况下？
Don't be a fool! You're gonna try to sing?! In your condition?
我应该是一个步行者！
I'm supposed to be a WalkUre!
我本应该是一个步行者，但。。。
I'm supposed to be a WalkUre, but...
我说，“不管发生什么”，但是。。。
I said, "no matter what happens," but...
为什么我…我害怕。。。
Why am I... I'm scared...
我不敢唱歌。
I'm afraid to sing.
我害怕死！
I'm scared of dying!
我应该是一个步行者。瓦库里应该通过唱歌来保护每个人。
I'm supposed to be a WalkUre. A Wa|kUre's supposed to protect everyone by singing.
但我不能…我不会唱歌。
But I can't... I can't sing.
我好害怕。。。
I'm so scared...
|-|恐怕我不能再和你在一起了！
|-|'m afraid I won't be able to be with you anymore!
弗雷亚”
Freyia"
我该怎么办？
What should I do?
我该怎么办，海亚特？
What should I do, Hayate?
你必须停止唱歌。
You have to stop singing.
那我就不再是步行者了。
Then I'll no longer be a WalkUre.
海亚特，你能不飞而活吗？
Can you live without flying, Hayate?
我会保护温德米尔！我保证。
I'll protect Windermere! I promise.
所以我想让你活着。
So I want you to live.
我要你继续活下去！
I want you to live on!
我想和你一起生活。
I want to live my life with you.
我也是。。。
So do I...
我也想和你在一起，海亚特。
I want to be with you too, Hayate.
但是
But...
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
你和我，我保证。。。
You and me, I promise...
在沉默中淡出
Fade away in silence
（/喜欢独处）
(/ prefer being alone)
黑暗太深了
Darkness is so much
比l/lght更漂亮
more beautiful than l/lght
$0你想保护什么？
$0 what are you trying to protect?
你在里面呆了这么久，你会
You're so week inside, you'll
你自己打碎
break into pieces yourself
我们是来解放银河系的
We're here to free the galaxy
旋律正在奏响我们来这里是为了解放银河系
A melody is playing We're here to free the galaxy
正在播放旋律
A melody is playing
一首曲子正在演奏着M女士，她试图阻止我们的人类文明，
A melody is playing of Lady M, who intends to prevent our human civilization,
打算阻止我们人类文明的M女士，
of Lady M, who intends to prevent our human civilization,
仔细听M女士说，她打算阻止我们的人类文明，
Listen closely of Lady M, who intends to prevent our human civilization,
仔细听
Listen closely
仔细聆听进化。
Listen closely from evolving.
从进化开始。
From evolving.
这是不可避免的命运……来自进化。
It's inescapable destiny... from evolving.
这是不可避免的命运。。。
It's inescapable destiny...
这是不可避免的命运……时机已经成熟！
It's inescapable destiny... The time has come to rise!
这是不可避免的命运。。。
It's inescapable destiny...
这是不可避免的命运……部署所有部队！
It's inescapable destiny... Deploy all forces!
Iris开始-Desz’r0y-结束的声音
Iris begun -Desz'r0y- The sound of the end
已经挂断电话了，别挡我的路
has rung out, don't get in my way
像天使一样，从你的D./\/.A深处
Like an Angel, from the depths of your D./\/.A
唱毁灭之歌，就像你在尖叫
Sing devastation, like you're screaming
唱毁灭性的歌，就像你在尖叫一样。正如所料，在联合国军队中爆发了叛乱行为。
Sing devastation, like you're screaming As expected, acts of insurrection have broken out within N.U.N.S. ranks.
唱毁灭之歌，就像你在尖叫
Sing devastation, like you're screaming
唱毁灭之歌，就像你在尖叫。以这种速度，它很可能导致
Sing devastation, like you're screaming At this rate, it may well lead to
以这种速度，很可能导致
At this rate, it may well lead to
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。邪恶以这种速度，很可能导致
Evil. Evil. You too are evil. Evil At this rate, it may well lead to
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。恶毒的
Evil. Evil. You too are evil. Evil
恶毒的恶毒的你也是邪恶的。银河系的邪恶全面战争。
Evil. Evil. You too are evil. Evil all-out war across the galaxy.
在内心深处，你一定已经知道我们会在那之前干掉克伦威尔。
Deep inside, you must already know We'll take out Cromwell before that happens.
在内心深处，你一定已经知道了
Deep inside, you must already know
在内心深处，你一定已经知道进入A|fheim的防线。
Deep inside, you must already know Entering A|fheim's defense perimeter.
但否认。否认说谎者。你必须/我/开始Jérmungand行动！
But deny. Deny. Liar. You st/l/ Commencing Operation Jérmungandr!
但否认。否认说谎者。你必须/我/
But deny. Deny. Liar. You st/l/
哈哈！似乎已经够痛了。
ha van'! had enough pain, it seems.
企业价值//。企业价值//。我很邪恶。恶毒的
EV//. EV//. lam evil. Evil
-lz赢了！停下，-《堕落天使之歌》
-lz' won'! stop, -z'he song of fallen angels
-现在全部-w//l吞没
-Now all -w/// l engulf
-现在，我吞没了所有的突击队战士！
-Now all -w/// l engulf Launch all assault team fighters!
启动所有突击队战士！
Launch all assault team fighters!
来吧。一个黑暗而冰冷的世界，发射所有突击队战士！
Come on. A dark and frozen world Launch all assault team fighters!
来吧，一个黑暗而冰冷的世界
Come on. A dark and frozen world
拜托，一个黑暗而冰冷的世界，你当上了幻影飞行指挥官？
Come on. A dark and frozen world You made Mirage flight commander?
你被任命为幻影飞行指挥官？
You made Mirage flight commander?
我给你看，你是幻影飞行指挥官？
I will show you You made Mirage flight commander?
你被任命为幻影飞行指挥官？
You made Mirage flight commander?
深渊你做了幻影飞行指挥官？
The abyss You made Mirage flight commander?
深渊
The abyss
你会看到，万丈深渊耐心。
The abyss Patience, you'll see.
深渊
The abyss
海亚特。。。
Hayate...
我明白了。
I get it.
我不可能马上接替梅瑟的位置。
There's no way I can fill Messer's shoes right away.
但是，我仍然想像他那样保护人们。
But still, I want to protect people like he did.
我也是。
So do I.
白色骑士。。。
White Knight...
他只是说我们都有同样的感觉，深红骑士！
He's just saying we all feel the same, Crimson Knight!
我收到了我的命令。我将被转移到Laram/s系统。
I received my orders. I'm t0 be transferred t0 the Laram/s System.
哦
Oh.
银河系的那一部分仍然没有受到Var综合征的影响，这是安全的。
Well that part 0f the galaxy is still untouched by the Var Syndrome, it's safe.
所以，你将成为那里的飞行教练。祝你好运好吗？
So, you're going to be a flight instructor there. Good luck okay?
非常感谢。
Thank you.
L1“看起来像/”//能带上我的瓦尔基里。
L1' looks like /'// be able to take my Valkyrie with me.
尽管我怀疑我们会看到更多的实战。
Although I doubt we'll see any more actual combat.
即便如此，/’//继续飞行，卡内姆小姐。
Even so, /'// keep flying Miss Kaname.
Messer。。。
Messer...
然后，继续唱歌。
Then /'// keep singing too.
梅瑟，指引我们。
Messer, guide us.
我再也跟不上了
I could never keep up
你总是
You were always
看着我们的东西
Looking our at something
从这个地方
from this place
算上那些事情，
Counting those things that,
一旦着魔，
once possessed,
一旦拥有，超级折叠门同步成功！
once possessed, Super Fold Gate synchronization successful!
超级折叠门同步成功！
Super Fold Gate synchronization successful!
丢失的超级折叠门同步成功！
Are lost Super Fold Gate synchronization successful!
都迷路了
Are lost
都迷路了所有部队，撤退！
are lost All forces, move in!
都迷路了
Are lost
你藏着眼泪，
You were hiding your tears,
你藏着眼泪，舰队航向调整完成。
You were hiding your tears, Fleet course adjustment complete.
车队路线调整完成。
Fleet course adjustment complete.
你是2岁吗？车队路线调整完成。
Weren '2' you? Fleet course adjustment complete.
你是2岁吗？
Weren '2' you?
你是2岁吗？所有船只，全速前进！
Weren '2' you? All ships, full speed ahead!
塔尔烈性
Thar intense
你的凝视
gaze of yours
您的超级折叠成功！
gaze of yours Super Fold successful!
看到了这个世界
Saw the world
看到世界三角洲航班，离开！
Saw the world Delta Flight, move out!
看到了这个世界
Saw the world
以不同的l/ghz
in a different l/ghz'
梦想
Dreams
梦想敌人舰队已经进入系统。
Dreams Enemy fleet has entered the system.
只有“2”号到达了，他们已经通过了超级折叠门！
Aren '2' reached alone They've come through the Super Fold Gate!
仅到达竞技场“2”
Aren '2' reached alone
只有“2”号了哼，太晚了！
aren '2' reached alone Heh, they're too late!
它们在可见的风中飞向我们
They f/y to us on in visible winds
Per/sh/ng是摇头丸
Per/sh/ng is ecstasy
另一扇门？！
Another gate?!
它似乎与子空间相连。
It seems to be connected to subspace.
使用折叠雷达扫描。
Scanning with Fold Radar.
让我们用折叠雷达进行更多扫描。
Let's p/a y some more Scanning with Fold Radar.
我们再来点吧
Let's p/a y some more
我们再来一点那是。。。！
Let's p/a y some more That's...!
我们再来点吧
Let's p/a y some more
这个/sn'2'接近/y就够了
This /sn '2' near/y enough
不知你能否联系到我The Megaroad-O1！
Wonder if you can reach me The Megaroad-O1!
不知道你能不能联系到我
Wonder if you can reach me
不知道你能不能联系到我，时间到了！
Wonder if you can reach me The time has come!
时间到了！
The time has come!
（来吧，过来）时间到了！
(Come on, over here) The time has come!
（来吧，这边）
(Come on, over here)
（来吧，到这里来）现在我们将实现我们一直为之奋斗的目标！
(Come on, over here) Now we will achieve what we have fought for all this time!
现在，我们将实现我们一直奋斗的目标！
Now we will achieve what we have fought for all this time!
让我看到你在奋斗，听到你在哭泣，现在我们将实现我们一直奋斗的目标！
Let me see you struggle, hear you wail Now we will achieve what we have fought for all this time!
让我看到你挣扎，听到你哭泣
Let me see you struggle, hear you wail
G0开，断开
G0 on, break
伪君子天真的笑容
The innocent smile of hypocrites
伪君子天真的笑容保护M女士！
The innocent smile of hypocrites Protect Lady M!
伪君子天真的笑容
The innocent smile of hypocrites
伪君子天真的笑容开始沉默行动！
The innocent smile of hypocrites Commence Operation Silence!
开始沉默行动！
Commence Operation Silence!
是一个罪恶的梦开始行动沉默！
Is a sinful dream Commence Operation Silence!
是一个罪恶的梦
Is a sinful dream
是一个罪恶的梦-罗杰！-噢，先生！
is a sinful dream - Roger! - Oorah sir!
是一个罪恶的梦
Is a sinful dream
啊
Ah
所以他们的策略是干扰所有的折叠波，甚至他们自己的歌曲。
So their strategy is to jam all Fold Waves, even their own songs.
折叠干扰成功。。。
Fold Jamming successful...
请记住，WalkUre的演唱在干扰期间也会失去效果。
Remember that WalkUre's singing will also lose its effect during jamming.
让我们快点！
Let's make this quick!
三角洲5号，不要破坏队形！
Delta 5, don't break formation!
三角洲3号，三点钟的强盗。。。
Delta 3, the bandit at three o'clock...
不，跟着塔纳托斯队形走！
No, go with the Thanatos formation!
抓紧，幻影！
Get a grip, Mirage!
我们会在干扰有效的时候把他们干掉！
We'll take them out while the jamming is effective!
所有部队，准备发射巨炮！
All forces, prepare for Macross Cannon discharge!
所有船舶开始改造。
All ships commencing transformation.
连接动力传输系统
Connecting power transfer system
他们的歌声。。。
Their singing...
我听不到他们的歌声。。。
I can't hear their singing...
所有战士必须立即清除火线。
All fighters are to clear the line of fire immediately.
我重复，所有战士都要立即清除火线。
I repeat', all fighters are to clear the line of fire immediate/y.
能源费为730%。
Energy charge at 730%.
所有飞船，开火！
All ships, fire your Macross Cannons!
他们的屏障被加固了。
Their barrier's been reinforced.
干扰系统。。。
The jamming system's...
被反击了！
been countered!
这就是警报器系统的力量。壮丽的
So this is the power of the Siren System. Magnificent!
Walkiire对我们没有任何用处。
Walkiire is of no further use to us.
摧毁他们！消灭M女士那些可恶的女神！
Destroy them! Wipe out those accursed goddesses of Lady M!
（倾倒）反正你现在是奴隶了
(Pouring) You're a// slaves now anyway
（倾倒）不管怎么说，你现在是奴隶了超级折叠门又出现了！
(Pouring) You're a// slaves now anyway The Super Fold Gates are reappearing!
超级折叠门又出现了！
The Super Fold Gates are reappearing!
（咬）不要假装酷，不要不要不要，超级折叠门又出现了！
(Biting) N0 use pretending to be cool, no no no no The Super Fold Gates are reappearing!
（咬）不要用假装酷，不不不不
(Biting) N0 use pretending to be cool, no no no no
（咬）不要用装酷，不要不要不要不要这个角度！
(Biting) N0 use pretending to be cool, no no no no This angle!
（懒惰）我的意思是，你拿着它r/ghz？这太糟糕了！
(Lazy) I mean, you're holding it r/ghz'? This is bad!
（懒惰）我的意思是，你拿着它r/ghz？
(Lazy) I mean, you're holding it r/ghz'?
（懒惰）我的意思是，你拿着它r/ghz？他们的火力线因
(Lazy) I mean, you're holding it r/ghz'? Their line of fire has shifted due to
（懒惰）我的意思是，你拿着它r/ghz？
(Lazy) I mean, you're holding it r/ghz'?
（懒惰）我的意思是，你拿着它r/ghz？温德米尔的行星旋转！
(Lazy) I mean, you're holding it r/ghz'? Windermere's planetary rotation!
温德米尔的行星旋转！
Windermere's planetary rotation!
邀请帮助/温德米尔行星旋转！
An invitation to hel/ Windermere's planetary rotation!
邀请帮忙/
An invitation to hel/
邀请帮助/如果他们用他们的
An invitation to hel/ If they fire on the Megaroad-O1 with their
如果他们用他们的
If they fire on the Megaroad-O1 with their
（惊慌失措）Iris是个死胡同，/估计如果他们用他们的
(Abashed) Iris a dead end, / reckon If they fire on the Megaroad-O1 with their
（羞愧）我想艾丽斯是个死胡同
(Abashed) Iris a dead end, I reckon
（羞愧）艾瑞斯是个死胡同，我认为超超时空加农炮就在那个位置。。。
(Abashed) Iris a dead end, I reckon Hyper Macross Cannon from that position...
那个位置上的超宏观加农炮。。。
Hyper Macross Cannon from that position...
（索格）你是一群r/ffrafij甚至站在那个位置上的st/l/超微距加农炮。。。
(Soggy) You're a bunch of r/ffrafij even standing st/l/ Hyper Macross Cannon from that position...
（Soggy）你甚至站在圣路易斯岛上都是一帮难民/
(Soggy) You're a bunch of r/ffrafij even standing st/l/
（索格）你是一群混蛋，即使站在圣里温德米尔也会。。。
(Soggy) You're a bunch of r/ffrafij even standing st/l/ Windermere will be...
温德米尔将。。。
Windermere will be...
（哎哟）/转眼间，这个世界将变成温德米尔。。。
(Ouch) /n an instant, this world becomes Windermere will be...
（哎哟）/一瞬间，这个世界变成了
(Ouch) /n an instant, this world becomes
猥亵的监狱
an indecent prison
但是，但是，但是你
But, but, but you
但是，但是，但是你什么？！
But, but, but you What?!
但是，但是，但是你
But, but, but you
忘记了这一点
oblivious to this
忘了这难道没有办法阻止他们开枪吗？！
oblivious to this Isn't there some way to stop them from firing?!
欣喜若狂地反对虚假的爱情唯一的办法就是摧毁他们船上的系统！
Are ecstatic aver a fake love The only way is to destroy the system inside their ship!
欣喜若狂的人反对虚假的爱情吗
Are ecstatic aver a fake love
都欣喜若狂地反对一个虚假的爱情卜！怎样
are ecstatic aver a fake love Bu! how?
欣喜若狂的人反对虚假的爱情吗
Are ecstatic aver a fake love
欣喜若狂地否认与Wa|kiJre的歌声的虚假爱情！
are ecstatic aver a fake love With Wa|kiJre's singing!
燃烧，拥抱，哭泣，后悔，就是这样！如果我们提高
Burn, embrace, cry, regret That's it! If we boost our
燃烧、拥抱、哭泣、后悔
Burn, embrace, cry, regret
用我们的歌声燃烧、拥抱、哭泣、后悔|i|‘Kairos Plus’的力量。。。
Burn, embrace, cry, regret |i|' Kairos Plus' power with our singing...
|我|“Kairos Plus”的力量与我们的歌唱。。。
|i|' Kairos Plus' power with our singing...
用我们的歌声粉碎我，吸吮我的“Kairos Plus”力量。。。
Shatter me, suck an me |i|' Kairos Plus' power with our singing...
粉碎我，吮吸我
Shatter me, suck an me
粉碎我，吮吸我，它可能会突破他们的维度障碍。
Shatter me, suck an me It might be able to break through their dimensional barrier.
它可能能够突破他们的维度障碍。
It might be able to break through their dimensional barrier.
腐化了我，它可能能够突破他们的维度障碍。
Corrupt me It might be able to break through their dimensional barrier.
毁了我
Corrupt me
到了我骨子里
to the very marrow of my bones
Wr/the，瘫痪，着迷，溺水
Wr/the, be paralyzed, be mesmerized, drown
来找我
Come to me
来找我-反弹头！-多个热信号传入！
Come to me - Reaction warheads! - Multiple heat signatures incoming!
所有部队从三点钟的高度拦截来袭的导弹。
All forces, intercept incoming missiles from three o'clock high.
防止他们袭击主力舰队！
Prevent them from hitting the main fleet!
HQge/j公司/
HQge/j/
他们成功了！
They got though!
我们还没做完！
We ain't done yet!
向右舷升起定点障碍物！
Raise Pinpoint Barriers to starboard!
全体人员，做好准备迎接冲击！
All hands, brace for impact!
贪婪的0美元曾经诱惑过。如何治疗
$0 greedy once seduced. How cure
贪婪的0美元曾经诱惑过。怎么治好了哟，她还完好无损！
$0 greedy once seduced. How cure Whew, she's still intact!
哟，她还完好无损！
Whew, she's still intact!
如果每个人都是英雄，那就太无聊了。哎呀，她仍然完好无损！
It'd be such a bore if everyone were a hero Whew, she's still intact!
如果每个人都是英雄，那会很无聊
It'd be such a bore if everyone were a hero
如果在75%的冲锋率下每个人都是英雄，那真是令人厌烦。
It'd be such a bore if everyone were a hero Main guns at' 75% charge.
如果每个人都是英雄，那会很无聊
It'd be such a bore if everyone were a hero
如果每个人都是英雄，那会很无聊不！
It'd be such a bore if everyone were a hero No!
如果我们不阻止他们，Megaroad-O1将。。。
If we don't stop them, Megaroad-O1 will...
Yern，amass，ido/ize，worsh/p女士Mwi||。。。！
Yearn, amass, ido/ize, worsh/p Lady M wi||...!
年份、聚集、ido/ize、worsh/p
Yearn, amass, ido/ize, worsh/p
Yern，amass，ido/ize，worsh/p Windermere wi||。。。！
Yearn, amass, ido/ize, worsh/p Windermere wi||...!
年份、聚集、ido/ize、worsh/p
Yearn, amass, ido/ize, worsh/p
Yern，amass，ido/ize，worsh/p银河系的平衡将被破坏！
Yearn, amass, ido/ize, worsh/p The balance of the galaxy will be destroyed!
燃烧、拥抱、哭泣、后悔
Burn, embrace, cry, regret
粉碎我，吮吸我
Shatter me, suck an me
腐败我
corrupt me
腐化我该死的你！
corrupt me Damn you!
该死的你！
Damn you!
到我骨子里去该死的你！
To the very marrow of my bones Damn you!
到了我骨子里
To the very marrow of my bones
就在你身后的Delta 6'我的骨髓里/
to the very marrow of my bones Delta 6', behind y0u./
到了我骨子里
to the very marrow of my bones
你以为我纯洁、洁白、干净
You thought I was pure, white and clean
你是谁？
D/dn '2' you?
你是谁？海亚特·勒梅尔曼！
D/dn '2' you? Hayate lmmelmann!
海亚特·勒梅尔曼！
Hayate lmmelmann!
塔尔不会的。漂亮的花是海亚特·勒梅尔曼！
Thar won't do. Pretty flowers are Hayate lmmelmann!
塔尔不会的。漂亮的花是
Thar won't do. Pretty flowers are
塔尔不会的。美丽的花朵是我发誓要保卫温德米尔的！
Thar won't do. Pretty flowers are I vow to defend Windermere!
塔尔不会的。漂亮的花是
Thar won't do. Pretty flowers are
塔尔不会的。美丽的花朵那里善良的人们，苹果园，我会保护他们！
Thar won't do. Pretty flowers are The kind people there, the apple orchards, I'll defend them all!
那里善良的人们，苹果园，我会保护他们！
The kind people there, the apple orchards, I'll defend them all!
Po/Zsonous，/告诉你。（G0因邪恶而疯狂）那里善良的人们，苹果园，我会保护他们所有人！
Po/Zsonous, / tell you. (G0 mad with wickedness) The kind people there, the apple orchards, I'll defend them all!
有毒，我告诉你。（因邪恶而发疯）
Poisonous, I tei/ you. (Go mad with wickedness)
有毒，我告诉你。（为邪恶疯狂）总有一天，我会摆脱
Poisonous, I tel/ you. (Go mad with wickedness) And one day, I'll rid
总有一天，我会摆脱
And one day, I'll rid
跳舞，可能和白天。（G0爱得发狂）总有一天，我会摆脱
Dance, might and day. (G0 mad with love) And one day, I'll rid
跳舞，可能和白天。（G0因爱而疯狂）
Dance, might and day. (G0 mad with love)
跳舞，可能和白天。（G0爱得发狂）所有战争的银河系！
Dance, might and day. (G0 mad with love) the galaxy of all war!
跳舞，可能和白天。（G0因爱而疯狂）
Dance, might and day. (G0 mad with love)
这种毒药很厉害。（G0因黑暗而疯狂）那么Frey/a可以
The poison is potent. (G0 mad with darkness) Then Frey/a can
这种毒药很厉害。（G0在黑暗中疯狂）
The poison is potent. (G0 mad with darkness)
这种毒药很厉害。（G0因黑暗而疯狂）再次与Wa/kLira一起歌唱！
The poison is potent. (G0 mad with darkness) sing with Wa/kLira again!
再次用Wa/kLire唱歌！
Sing with Wa/kLire again!
唱吧，n/ghz’and day。是 啊再次与Wa/kLire一起歌唱！
Sing, n/ghz' and day. Yeah! sing with Wa/kLire again!
唱吧，n/jghz’and day。是 啊
Sing, n/jghz' and day. Yeah!
唱吧，n/jghz’and day。是 啊哈亚·哈亚。。。
Sing, n/jghz' and day. Yeah! Haya-Haya...
唱吧，n/jghz’and day。是 啊
Sing, n/jghz' and day. Yeah!
唱吧，n/jghz’and day。是 啊每天，温柔的歌声。
Sing, n/jghz' and day. Yeah! Everyday, tender songs.
每天，温柔的歌声。
Everyday, tender songs.
有毒，我告诉你。（因邪恶而疯狂）每天，温柔的歌曲。
Poisonous, I tel/ you. (Go mad with wickedness) Everyday, tender songs.
有毒，我告诉你。（因邪恶而发疯）
Poisonous, I tei/ you. (Go mad with wickedness)
有毒，我告诉你。（对邪恶疯狂）不是为了阻止战争。
Poisonous, I tel/ you. (Go mad with wickedness) Not for stopping wars.
跳舞，可能和白天。（G0因爱而疯狂）
Dance, might and day. (G0 mad with love)
跳舞，可能和白天。（G0爱得发狂）阿哈三角洲航班可以飞越天空，
Dance, might and day. (G0 mad with love) Aha' Delta Flight can f/ y the skies,
安娜三角洲航班可以飞越天空，
Ana' Delta Flight can f/ y the skies,
这种毒药对你很有效。（在黑暗中发疯）安娜三角洲航班可以飞越天空，
The poison is potent I te// you. (Go mad with darkness) Ana' Delta Flight can f/ y the skies,
毒药很厉害，我把你摔倒了。（在黑暗中发疯）
The poison is potent I fell you. (Go mad with darkness)
毒药很厉害，我把你摔倒了。（在黑暗中发疯）跟着他们的歌。
The poison is potent I fell you. (Go mad with darkness) along to their song.
毒药很厉害，我把你摔倒了。（在黑暗中发疯）
The poison is potent I fell you. (Go mad with darkness)
毒药很厉害，我把你摔倒了。（在黑暗中发疯）海亚特。。。
The poison is potent I fell you. (Go mad with darkness) Hayate...
唱吧，n/jghz’and day。是 啊我们将生活下去。
Sing, n/jghz' and day. Yeah! We'll live life.
唱吧，n/jghz’and day。是 啊
Sing, n/jghz' and day. Yeah!
唱吧，n/jghz’and day。是 啊我们一起唱。一起飞翔。
Sing, n/jghz' and day. Yeah! We'll sing together. Fly together.
我们一起唱。一起飞翔。
We'll sing together. Fly together.
解毒是徒劳的，我们一起唱。一起飞翔。
Detoxification is futile We'll sing together. Fly together.
戒毒是徒劳的
Detoxification is futile
戒毒是徒劳的我们会一起生活！
Detoxification is futile We'll live life together!
戒毒是徒劳的
Detoxification is futile
海亚特。。。
Hayate...
歌曲和风，一起。。。
Both song and wind, together...
不会放弃，不会放弃，
Won't give up, won't give up,
Freyja？！
Freyja?!
W0“：911,6，以上
W0”: ' 911,6, up
我是Freyja。
It's Freyja.
I76 V6f 6 V6！"
I76 V6f 6 V6!"
现在，现在，现在这个声音。。。
Now, now, now, That voice...
现在，现在，如何，
Now, now, HOW,
现在，现在，现在不可能。。。
Now, now, now, No way...
我能听到某人的声音
I can hear someoneis voice
-弗雷亚！-弗雷弗雷！
- Freyja! - Fre-Fre!
Freyja，不要！
Freyja, don't!
你必须躺在床上！
You've got to stay in bed!
“你活着是为了什么？你唱歌是为了什么……”
"For what do you live? For what do you sing..."
对不起，约翰神父。
I'm sorry, Father Johann.
对不起，海亚特。。。
Sorry, Hayate...
但我要唱歌了。
But I'm going to sing.
因为我是步行者！
Because I'm a Walkilre!
Freyja，你。。。
Freyja, you...
但在你的州。。。
But in your state...
我想和你一起生活！
I want to live life, together with you Kaname!
还有米库莫。
And Mikumo.
还有马基纳。
And Makina.
还有雷纳。
And Reina.
我想和每个人一起生活。
I want to live life together with everyone.
“想要生活。。。
"Want to live life...
在一起
Together...
与每个人“？
With everyone"?
对我来说，生活意味着
To me, living means
像散步一样唱歌！
singing as a Walkilre!
我想继续和你们大家一起散步！
I want to continue living as a Walkilre with you all!
我没有退缩！不谈生活，不谈唱歌，不谈恋爱。
I'm not holding back! Not on life, not on singing, not on... love.
没有退缩。。。
Not holding back...
我要活下去。把我的生命活到尽头。我要绝对活着！绝对地
I'm gonna live. Live my life to the end. I wanna be absolutely alive! Absolutely!
弗雷亚”
Freyia"
我也想和你一起生活，弗雷弗雷！
I wanna live life together with you too, Fre-Fre!
对让我们一起生活。
Yes. Let's live life, together.
没有别的办法了。WalkiJre绝对必须是我们五个人。
There's no other way. WalkiJre absolutely has to be all five of us.
我也想生活。
I want to live life too.
Mikumo、Makina、Reina和Freyja。
Mikumo, Makina, Reina, and Freyja.
我绝对想和你们一起活到最后！
I absolutely want to live to the very end, together with all of you!
卡奈姆。。。
Kaname...
好吧让我们唱歌！
Alright! Let's sing!
我们的生命之歌！绝对地
Our life's song! Absolutely!
Mikumo…你说对了！
Mikumo... You betcha!
为了银河系。
For the galaxy.
对于外面的人。
For someone out there.
我们打算。。。
We are going to...
全力以赴。
Give it all we've got.
尽情享受吧，就像这是我们最后一次一样！
Enjoy it as though it's our last!
去沃尔基尔！
Go! Walkiire!
不放弃，不放弃，不会放弃，
Won't give up, won't give up, won't give up,
I76 V6f 6 V6！"
I76 V6f 6 V6!"
不
No!
让我们一起生活吧，Freyja！
Let's live life together, Freyja!
海亚特！
Hayate!
我会保护你Freyja。
I'll protect you Freyja.
我们保护WalkUre！Delta Flight就是这么做的！
We protect WalkUre! That's what Delta Flight does!
飞吧，海亚特！我会唱歌！
Fly, Hayate! I'll sing!
现在，现在，现在我能听到某人的声音
Now, now, now, I can hear someonefis voice
歌曲、歌曲、歌曲，/都是由星星的牵引力引导的。苹果园。
Songs, songs, songs, /'m guided by the pull of the stars Winderemere. The apple orchards.
歌曲、歌曲、歌曲，/由星星的牵引力引导
Songs, songs, songs, /'m guided by the pull of the stars
歌曲、歌曲、歌曲，都是由星星的牵引力引导的，我们自己绝对要把它们夺回！
Songs, songs, songs, /'n1 guided b y the pull of the stars We're absolutely taking them back ourselves!
让那神秘的声音响彻天空
Let f/y that mysterious sound (f/y t0 the sky)
让那神秘的声音响彻天空，三角洲飞行，我们走！
Let f/y that mysterious sound (f/y t0 the sky) Delta Flight, let's go!
让那神秘的声音响彻天空
Let f/y that mysterious sound (f/y t0 the sky)
让那神秘的声音飞向天空Ooreh先生/
Let fly that mysterious sound (fly t0 the sky) - De! — Ooreh sir./
_噢，先生！
_ D3] - Oorah sir!
我想送他们去宇宙（飞向星星）-德！-哦，先生！
I want to send them t0 the cosmos (fly to the stars) - De! — Ooreh sir!
我想把它们送到宇宙（飞向星星）
I want to send them to the cosmos (fly to the stars)
一首我渴望的旋律
A melody that al/jgns with the l/ght I yearn for
耶耶耶耶
Yeah yeah yeah
哦，天哪，让你的诞生之声（唤醒）沃尔基Jre的生物折叠波正在迅速增加。
Oh nob/e heart, let out your birth cry (awaken) WalkiJre's Bio-Fold Waves are increasing rapidly.
哦，亲爱的，让你的诞生之声响起（唤醒）
Oh nob/e heart, let out your birth cry (awaken)
噢，亲爱的，让你的诞生之声（唤醒），这样他们仍然可以歌唱。
Oh nob/e heart, let out your birth cry (awaken) So they can still sing.
所以他们仍然可以唱歌。
So they can still sing.
在变化的时代里，一起唱歌，这样他们仍然可以唱歌。
Sing together, amidst changing times So they can still sing.
在瞬息万变的时代里，一起歌唱
Sing together, amidst changing times
在瞬息万变的时代里，一起歌唱的确是M女士自己选择的一种强大的音乐武器。
Sing together, amidst changing times Indeed a formidable musical weapon, chosen by Lady M herself.
在瞬息万变的时代里，一起歌唱
Sing together, amidst changing times
在变化的时代里，一起唱歌。塞伦对他们进行研究是有益的。
Sing together, amidst changing times It was beneficial that Siren studied them.
Siren研究它们是有益的。
It was beneficial that Siren studied them.
决心的呼喊！还没有，还没有，尚未，尚未！Siren研究它们是有益的。
A howl of determination! Not yet, not yet, not yet, not yet! It was beneficial that Siren studied them.
决心的呼喊！还没有，还没有，尚未，尚未！
A howl of determination! Not yet, not yet, not yet, not yet!
不会放弃，不会！让出一英寸，
Won't give up, Won'! give an inch,
没有实现，爱在哭泣
unfulfilled, love is crying
独自承受i2'的优点？“2”不需要它！
The virtue of bearing i2' alone? Don '2' need it!
心在呼唤彼此，
Hearts calling out to each other,
心在呼唤着彼此，我能看到！
Hearts calling out to each other, I can see it!
团结起来，释放出共鸣的歌曲
Uniting to unleash a resonating song
团结起来，释放出一首共鸣的歌曲，我可以看到风！
uniting to unleash a resonating song I can see the wind!
让我感觉你很深
Let me feel you deep/y, deep/y
超越时空！
beyond time and space!
不放弃，不放弃，不会放弃，
Won't give up, won't give up, won't give up,
让i2'更好
make i2' better
我想让我打电话给我们
I want to make i2' ring our, ring out, ring out
我想让我打电话给我们，打电话，打电话我跟不上了！
I want to make i2' ring our, ring out, ring out I can't keep up!
我跟不上了！
I can't keep UP!
无尽的/y我跟不上了！
Endless/y I can't keep up!
无止境/年
Endless/y
我能看到它！
I can see it!
从这里，我可以看到每个人的动作。
From here, I can see everyone's movements.
三角洲5号，硬下潜。
Delta 5, hard dive.
三角洲6，三点钟加35度。
Delta 6, three o'clock plus 35 degrees.
三角洲3号，10点+27度，稳定。
Delta 3, ten o'clock plus 27 degrees, steady.
什么
What?
日分！那里什么都没有。。。
Bu! there's nothing there...
这是命令！准备好！
That's an order! Get ready!
编队：中卫！
Formation: Midgard!
罗杰弗
Rogefl
让我更伤心，让我更感受
Break me more, feel me more
让我更受伤，感觉到我更多，目标在眼前？！
Break me more, feel me more Target in sight?!
你在吗？你在外面吗？我们就在他们的尾巴上！
Are you there? Are you out there? We're right 0n their tails!
你在吗？你在外面吗？
Are you there? Are you out there?
你在吗？你在外面吗？拿着这个！
Are you there? Are you out there? Take this!
拿着这个！
Take this!
战场上绽放的生命，拿着这个！
Life that blooms on the battlefield, Take this!
战场上绽放的生命，
Life that blooms on the battlefield,
让i2“燃烧，让i2”燃烧
let i2' burn, let i2' burn
如果我的命运即将消逝，那就结束我
End ma if my fate is to fade away
如果我的命运即将消逝，那就结束吧，指挥官！
End ma if my fate is to fade away Right on, commander!
如果我的命运即将消逝，那就结束我
End ma if my fate is to fade away
如果我的命运即将消逝，那就结束吧，太棒了！
End ma if my fate is to fade away That was great!
如果我的命运即将消逝，那就结束我
End ma if my fate is to fade away
如果我的命运即将消逝，那就结束我/
End ma if my fate is to fade away You read the w/nd./
你读了w/nd/
You read the w/nd./
燃烧，燃烧，在毁灭的尽头，你读着风/
Burning, burning, at the end of destruction You read the wind./
燃烧，燃烧，毁灭的终结
Burning, burning, at the end of destruction
燃烧，燃烧，在毁灭的尽头，我……我在飞翔我自己的天空！
Burning, burning, at the end of destruction I... I'm flying my own sky!
一、 ..我在飞翔我自己的天空！
I... I'm flying my own sky!
呼唤奇迹我…我在飞翔我自己的天空！
Call forth miracles I... I'm flying my own sky!
创造奇迹
Call forth miracles
在大海/天空中
in the sea/ed sky
大海/天空中美好的幻影。
in the sea/ed sky Good going Mirage.
在大海/天空中
In the sea/ed sky
海上/空中伽玛飞行至B7区域！
in the sea/ed sky Gamma Flight to area B7!
伽玛飞行到B7区域！
Gamma Flight to area B7!
我现在明白了，成为领导者的天赋。
I see now, the talent to be a leader.
我现在明白了，爱一个‘l/m/z’的领导者。
Love a2' the l/m/z', I see now, the talent to be a leader.
危险的/你的边界/屁股，iris疯了
Dangerous/y border/ass, iris just insane
然而/仍在加速
Yet /'m still accelerating
然而/仍在加速。你比我更适合担任主席。
Yet /'m still accelerating You're better suited for the chair than I am.
然而/仍在加速
Yet /'m still accelerating
然而/仍在加速我将把指挥权交给你，
Yet /'m still accelerating I'm leaving command to you,
我把指挥权交给你，
I'm leaving command to you,
舞得飞快/我把指挥权留给你了，
Dancing swift/y, I'm leaving command to you,
舞姿敏捷/年，
Dancing swift/y,
跳得很快，阿拉德船长！
Dancing swift/y, Captain Arad!
如果这是我的极限，继续摧毁我
If this is my limit, go ahead and destroy me
我是由马克斯制成的。
I am made from Max.
我是由
I am made from
我是因为我认识你很久了，
I am made from I've known you a long time,
我认识你很久了，
I've known you a long time,
毁灭和重生我认识你很久了，
destruction and rebirth I've known you a long time,
毁灭与重生
destruction and rebirth
我认为这是你做过的最好的决定。
destruction and rebirth and I think this is the best decision you've ever made.
让我们把它带到天空！
Let's take it to the skies!
爱a2'l/m/z'，
Love a2' the l/m/z',
禁区//他，不管挑战
the forbidden border//he, no matter the challenge
/'//突破i2'全部
/'// break through i2' all
/'//突破它a//-多棒啊。/-船长
/'// break through it a// - What a w/nd./ - Captain?
-多棒啊船长
- What a w/nd./ - Captain?
舞得飞快/y，-多大的风。/-船长
Dancing swift/y, - What a wind./ - Captain?
舞姿敏捷/年，
Dancing swift/y,
跳得很快，我不再是队长了。
Dancing swift/y, I'm no longer captain.
Pu///ng更多G’s，感官正在衰退，嗯？
Pu///ng even more G's, senses are fading Huh?
Pu//ng更多G’s，感官正在衰退
Pu///ng even more G's, senses are fading
pu///ng更多G’s，感官正在衰退我只是个天才！
pu///ng even more G's, senses are fading I'm just a genius!
Pu//ng更多G’s，感官正在衰退
Pu///ng even more G's, senses are fading
pu///ng更多G's，感官正在衰退这是。。。
pu///ng even more G's, senses are fading This is...
我的身体在控制着
My body is /as/ng control /'m gonna f/y away
我的身体失去控制/‘我要飞走了，警报器系统检测到不规则的波形！
My body is losing control /'n1 gonna fly away Irregular wave patterns detected in the Siren System!
我的身体在控制着
My body is /as/ng control /'m gonna f/y away
我的身体在控制着我的身体，它在学习什么？
My body is /as/ng control /'m gonna f/y away What is it learning?
我的身体在控制着
My body is /as/ng control /'m gonna f/y away
我的身体正在/作为/ng控制/将要/y远离超音速加农炮威力等级下降！
My body is /as/ng control /'m gonna f/y away Macross Cannon power level dropping!
巨炮威力等级下降！
Macross Cannon power level dropping!
达到随着爱（铅）巨炮威力的下降！
Reach! With love (lead) Macross Cannon power level dropping!
跳舞（我有空！）
Dance (I'm free!)
跳舞（我有空！）我会马上进行调整。
Dance (I'm free!) I will make adjustments right away.
我会马上进行调整。
I will make adjustments right away.
Fantasy Archr/um我会马上进行调整。
Fantasy Archr/um I will make adjustments right away.
梦幻乐园/um
Fantasy Archr/um
Fantasy Archr/um Alpha Flight，掩护Walkiire！
Fantasy Archr/um Alpha Flight, cover Walkiire!
Alpha Flight，掩护Walkiire！
Alpha Flight, cover Walkiire!
我们可以完成阿尔法飞行，掩护沃尔基尔！
We can do this Alpha Flight, cover Walkiire!
当你醒来时，/’//在你身边，/’//never lez’你会在9点钟以30度的角度再次前进，啮合/
When you wake, /'// be by your side, /'// never lez' you go again 9 o'clock at 30 degrees, engage./
当你醒来，/’//在你身边，/’//never lez’you go again
When you wake, /'// be by your side, /'// never lez' you go again
当你醒来时，/’//在你身边，/’/永远不要让你再去了，爸爸！
When you wake, /'// be by your side, /'// never lez' you go again Da!
当你醒来，/’//在你身边，/’//never lez’you go again
When you wake, /'// be by your side, /'// never lez' you go again
当你醒来，/’//在你身边，/’/永远不要离开你，白色骑士……借我你的风！
When you wake, /'// be by your side, /'// never lez' you go again White Knight... lend me your wind!
白骑士……借我你的风！
White Knight... lend me your wind!
我发誓（你是的）白骑士……借我你的风！
I swear (Your e yes) White Knight... lend me your wind!
白骑士……借我你的风！
White Knight... lend me your wind!
是耀眼的（狂风）白色骑士……借我你的风！
Are dazzling (squall) White Knight... lend me your wind!
白骑士……借我你的风！
White Knight... lend me your wind!
本能的冲动，幻影般的“0n”遗产，白色骑士……借我你的风！
A rush of instinct, a phantom ”0n ” legacy White Knight... lend me your wind!
本能的冲动，虚幻的“0n”遗产
A rush of instinct, a phantom ”0n ” legacy
寂静，永恒的空间
Silence, an everlasting space
真空I/ibe-ray-r/on
Vacuum I/ibe-ray-r/on
真空I/ibe-ray-r/on已理解。
Vacuum I/ibe-ray-r/on Understood.
真空I/ibe-ray-r/on
Vacuum I/ibe-ray-r/on
吸尘器I/ibe-ray-r/on Heir/e v/ng the Singer 0f the Dark并逃离-
Vacuum I/ibe-ray-r/on Heir/e v/ng the Singer 0f the Dark and making my escape-
你真傻。。。
That was foolish of you...
没有人能穿越艾司隆而活着。。。
No one crosses Epsilon and lives...
死亡
Die.
把所有能量都传给巨炮！
Direct all power to the Macross Cannon!
但是船不能接受！
But the ship can't take it!
它可能在开火时爆炸！
It might explode upon firing!
没关系。我命令全体船员弃船。
It doesn't matter. I'm ordering all crew to abandon ship.
海姆达尔革命将持续下去，
The Heimdall revolution will live on,
你将成为它的动力！
and you will be its driving force!
哈拯救！
Ha! Saverg!
接通强制能量充电。
Engaging forced energy charge.
上帝保佑你
God Bless You
我从来不知道我会/不会爱一个人这么多
I never knew I could /o ve someone this much
这种感觉永远不会
This feeling will never
-再次保持原样-G0d祝福你
-be the same again -G0d Bless You
这个世界上唯一的幸福
The only happiness in a World like this
世界上唯一的幸福就是这样一首多么美丽的歌。
The only happiness in a World like this What a beautiful song.
这个世界上唯一的幸福
The only happiness in a World like this
在这样一个世界上，唯一的幸福就是这个Freyja。。。
The only happiness in a World like this Freyja...
弗雷亚”
Freyia"
/分享我们的喜悦，Freyja。。。
/s sharing our joy, Freyja...
/分享我们的喜悦，
/s sharing our joy,
这些眼泪的原因
the reason for these tears
眼泪的原因生命之风。。。
the reason for these tears A wind of life...
这些眼泪的原因
the reason for these tears
眼泪的原因如此高贵。。。
the reason for these tears So regal...
这些眼泪的原因
the reason for these tears
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
还没，还没有，还没有/
Not yet, not yet, not yet, not yet/
不会放弃，不会！什么也不给，
Won't give up, won'! give nothing,
敲响希望之钟
ring the bell of hope
如果我们中有人失踪，我们就不完整了？这个不假思索！
We're incomplete if any one of us missing? The! goes without thinking!
五条路径形成五线sfaflj
Five paths form a five-line sfaflj
要流传下来的故事
a story to pass down
刻在我身上，炽热，
Carve i2' into me, blazing/y,
blazing/y，a2'l/ghz'的速度！
blazing/y, a2' the speed of l/ghz'!
人工重力系统损坏！
Artificial gravity system damaged!
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
三角洲5！关注乐队/ts！
Delta 5! Focus 0n the band/ts!
不会放弃，不会放弃，
Won't give up, won't give up,
歌曲是“2”种幻想
Songs aren '2' illusions
音乐并不是幻想
Music that can connect us is no fantasy
你能听到这个声音吗？
Can you hear this voice?
你在哭吗？
Are you crying?
你在笑吗？
Are you laughing?
/“//永远（在你身边）
/'// always be (at your side)
问这些问题
Asking these questions
闭上眼睛，仔细聆听你对我的记忆
Close your eyes, listen closely to your memory of me
闭上眼睛，仔细听你对我的记忆啊，他进步了。
Close your eyes, listen closely to your memory of me Ah, he's improved.
啊，他进步了。
Ah, he's improved.
我希望你能一直感觉到我在那里，所以不要！lez'g0./啊，他进步了。
I wam' you to always feel me there, so don'! lez' g0./ Ah, he's improved.
我希望你能一直感觉到我在那里，所以不要！列兹g0/
I wam' you to always feel me there, so don'! lez' g0./
伸出双手触摸我！看，/真的很温暖
Reach out with both hands and touch me! See, /'m really warm
伸出双手触摸我！看，我真的很热情，麦克斯指挥官！
Reach out with both hands and touch me! See, /'m really warm Commander Max!
伸出双手触摸我！看，/真的很温暖
Reach out with both hands and touch me! See, /'m really warm
伸出双手触摸我！看，/真的很温暖G0，lmme/mah！我已经成功了！你的背！
Reach out with both hands and touch me! See, /'m really warm G0, lmme/mahh! I've g0! your back!
伸出双手触摸我！看，/真的很温暖
Reach out with both hands and touch me! See, /'m really warm
伸出双手触摸我！看，我也很温暖！
Reach out with both hands and touch me! See, /'m really warm Me too!
我也是！
Me too!
说了一大堆话，我也是！
With a shower of words, Me too!
用一连串的话，
With a shower of words,
用一连串的话，安娜！
With a shower of words, Ana' me!
用一连串的话，
With a shower of words,
罗杰弗，滔滔不绝
With a shower of words, Rogefl
用一连串的话，
With a shower of words,
（你的一切）
(Your e veryth/ng)
我想念你。
I ho/d you.
还没有，还没有，尚未，尚未，还没有
Not yet, not yet, not yet, not yet, not yet, not yet
还没有，还没有，尚未，尚未，尚不，尚未，海亚特。。。
Not yet, not yet, not yet, not yet, not yet, not yet Hayate...
海亚特。。。
Hayate...
不会放弃，不会！让开一英寸，海亚特。。。
Won't give up, Won'! give an inch, Hayate...
不会放弃，不会！让出一英寸，
Won't give up, Won'! give an inch,
没有实现，爱在哭泣
unfulfilled, love is crying
独自承受i2'的优点？“2”不需要它！
The virtue of bearing i2' alone? Don '2' need it!
独自承受i2'的优点？“2”不需要它！电源不足。。。
The virtue of bearing i2' alone? Don '2' need it! Not enough power...
独自承受i2'的优点？“2”不需要它！
The virtue of bearing i2' alone? Don '2' need it!
独自承受的美德？不需要。/Delta 5，拿着这些！
The virtue of bearing it alone? Don 't need it./ Delta 5, take these!
心在呼唤彼此，
Hearts calling out to each other,
心在呼唤彼此，幽灵？！现在那是我们的指挥官！
Hearts calling out to each other, Ghosts?! Now that's our commander!
心在呼唤彼此，
Hearts calling out to each other,
团结起来，释放出共鸣的歌曲
uniting to unleash a resonating song
让我深深地感受你，
Let me feel you deep/y,
deep/y，超越时间和空间！
deep/y, beyond time and space!
深度/y，超越时间和空间！我们走了！
Deep/y, beyond time and space! Here we go!
深度/y，超越时间和空间！
Deep/y, beyond time and space!
不放弃，不放弃，不会放弃，
Won't give up, won't give up, won't give up,
只是想。。。
just wanna...
看透，看透，看透，
See it through, see it through, see it through,
直到最后
to the very end
海亚特！
Hayate!
去
Go!
G0凝胶！
G0 gel' 'em!
向前地
Forward!
再多一点！
Just a little more!
'54水果标准升/绿色是一
'54 fruit st/l/ green is one
被吸引是二
Being attracted is two
我的心在燃烧”
My heart is burning”
歌声重叠
The sound of singing overlaps
带着遥远的回忆
with distant memories
带着遥远的回忆Freyja！
with distant memories Freyja!
那是。。。
That's...
传奇之歌！
The song of legend!
路/将要走的路和我来的路
The way /'m going and the way I came
两者都没有错误
There are no mistakes in either
因为我很开心和满足（ha-）
Because I am happy and content (ha-)
让我们唱一首祈祷歌
Let us sing a song of prayer, that it
到达这片l/jghz海的遥远海岸
reaches the far shores of this sea of l/jghz'
梦想成真，我生命之火熊熊燃烧
A dream to fu/fi/l, the fire of my life burns
让我们通过音乐来表达活着的喜悦
Let us express through music the joy of being alive
我爱你
I love you
我们交易的话升天了
The words we trade rise to the heavens
低沉的旋律
A murmured melody
我能听到低沉的旋律！每个人都在唱歌。
A murmured melody I can hear it! Everyone's singing.
我能听到！每个人都在唱歌。
I can hear it! Everyone's singing.
在我的深处
Somewhere deep with/n me
它最终会变成一个星系
it becomes a galaxy, eventual/y
欢乐和悲伤
Joy and sorrow
欢乐与悲伤花儿。。。
Joy and sorrow Flowers...
欢乐和悲伤
Joy and sorrow
快乐和悲伤这是。。。
Joy and sorrow This is...
欢乐和悲伤
Joy and sorrow
给他们注入生命，让他们变得充实/…传奇。。。
breathe life into them so they become ful/ ...The legendary...
给他们注入生命，让他们变得充实/
breathe life into them so they become ful/
给他们注入生命，让他们变得充实/…符文花。。。
breathe life into them so they become ful/ ...Rune Flower...
给他们注入生命，让他们变得充实/
breathe life into them so they become ful/
仿佛在歌唱（ha-）
As if in song (ha-)
让那温柔的梦想
Let that tender dream
你把你的心戒指拿出来
you hold in your heart ring out
你把戒指放在心里哦，天哪！
you hold in your heart ring out Oh my gosh!
你把你的心戒指拿出来
You hold in your heart ring out
你把戒指放在心里，Yami_Q_ray，他们是。。。！
you hold in your heart ring out Yami_Q_ray, they're...!
你把你的心戒指拿出来
You hold in your heart ring out
你在心里唱着我们的歌！
you hold in your heart ring out singing our song!
你把你的心戒指拿出来
You hold in your heart ring out
爱之福，我的身体燃烧
Fu// of love, my body burns
我赞扬这种温暖
I commend this warmth
走向新的未来
to a new future
为了一个新的未来Freyja！
to a new future Freyja!
走向新的未来
To a new future
为了一个新的未来，让我们一起飞翔！
to a new future Let's fly together!
走向新的未来
To a new future
迈向新的未来-我们走！-走吧！
to a new future - Let's go! - Let's go!
让我们唱一首祈祷歌
Let us sing a song of prayer, that it
到达这片l/jghz海的遥远海岸
reaches the far shores of this sea of l/jghz'
梦想成真，我生命之火熊熊燃烧
A dream to fu/fi/l, the fire of my life burns
一个梦想，我的生命之火燃烧，唤醒。。。
A dream to fu/fi/l, the fire of my life burns To wake...
梦想成真，我生命之火熊熊燃烧
A dream to fu/fi/l, the fire of my life burns
梦想成真，我的生命之火燃烧着银河！
A dream to fu/fi/l, the fire of my life burns the galaxy!
梦想成真，我生命之火熊熊燃烧
A dream to fu/fi/l, the fire of my life burns
所有船只，开火！
All ships, fire!
海亚特！
Hayate!
海亚特。。。
Hayate...
你内心的呼唤
you ho/d in your heart ring our
爱之福，我的身体燃烧
Fu// of love, my body burns
我赞扬这种温暖，海亚特。。。
I commend this warmth Hayate...
我赞扬这种温暖
I commend this warmth
我赞扬这种温暖Sonofa。。。
I commend this warmth Sonofa...
我赞扬这种温暖
I commend this warmth
对于一个新的未来S0，“所有的风都是一体的。”
to a new future S0, "all Winds will be as one."
走向新的未来
To a new future
弗雷亚！
Freyja!
从我的心底
From the bottom of my heart
我爱你
I love you
-弗雷亚！-弗雷亚！
- Freyja! - Freyja!
弗雷娅…弗雷娅。
Freyja... Freyja.
弗雷亚”
Freyia"
海亚特。。。
Hayate...
所以这个婴儿是。。。
So this baby is...
是的……你用你的歌拯救了生命。
Yeah... a life you saved with your song.
哦，它在移动。
Oh, it's moving.
我不相信。。。
I don't believe it...
哦……一个符文。这是一个符文。
Oh... a rune. It's a rune.
非常感谢。谢谢你，海亚特。
Thank you. Thank you, Hayate.
是的……谢谢你，弗雷娅。
Yeah... thank you, Freyja.
你的歌唱感觉很好。一如既往。
Your singing felt pretty good. As always.
海亚特的lmmelmann舞蹈……也很像Gori Gori。
Hayate's lmmelmann Dance was... very Gori-Gori too.
爱之福，我的身体燃烧
Fu// of love, my body burns
爱之福，我的身体燃烧歌唱？
Fu// of love, my body burns Singing?
爱之福，我的身体燃烧
Fu// of love, my body burns
爱之福，我的身体燃烧花朵…每个人的符文花朵
Fu// of love, my body burns Flowers... Everyone's Rune Flowers
花…每个人的符文花
Flowers... Everyone's Rune Flowers
我赞扬这温暖的花朵…每个人的符文花朵
I commend this warmth Flowers... Everyone's Rune Flowers
我赞扬这种温暖
I commend this warmth
我赞扬这种温暖正在绽放。
I commend this warmth are blooming.
走向新的未来
To a new future
它真漂亮……看起来就像盛开的苹果花。
It's so beautiful... looks just like apple blossoms in bloom.
是的…太美了。
Yes... so beautiful.
花是白色的。
Flowers are white.
苹果是红色的。
Apples are red.
绿色的时候是酸的。
They're sour when they're green.
它们成熟时很甜。
They're sweet when they're ripe.
Gori甜。Gori很好吃。
Gori-sweet. Gori-tasty.
是的，他们很可爱。Gori很好吃。
Yeah, they're Gori-sweet. Gori-tasty.
Mercats很可爱。
Mercats are cute.
水母可以发光并漂浮在空中。
Jellyfish can glow and float in the sky.
孤独是孤独的。
Being alone is lonely.
和每个人在一起感觉很。。。
Being with everyone feels so...
-有趣-温暖的
- Fun. - Warm.
夕阳的紫色色调。
The purple hue of a sunset.
鸟儿的啁啾声。
The chirping of birds.
醒来的味道。
The smell of waking up.
雪地。
The snowy land.
风是柔和的。
The wind is gentle.
唱歌很有趣。
Singing is fun.
海亚特。。。
Hayate...
我爱你，海亚特。
I love you, Hayate.
我爱你，弗雷娅。
I love you, Freyja.
谢谢你，弗雷弗雷。。。
Thank you, Fre-Fre...
我们永远在一起，绝对。。。
We'll always be together, absolutely...
没错，我们是WalkUre。我们五岁，我们一岁。
That's right, we are WalkUre. We are five and we are one.
让我们继续唱生命之歌。
Let's continue to sing the song of life.
单词
The words
渗透到我的
seeping through my
干燥l/ps
parched l/ps
d/ss/pafe进入稀薄空气
d/ss/pafe into thin air
捡起我的破碎，
Picking up my broken,
空壳
empty shell
l1让我
l1' makes me
想听听你的声音
want to hear your voice
当我在开阔的天空上厕所时
When I loo/r up at the open sky
我的腿开始了
My legs start
再次摇晃
shaking again
尽管我想相信
Even though I want to believe
这个世界上的一切都有意义
that everything in this world has meaning
我还没决定，
My mind undecided,
我继续我的旅程
I continue my journey
但这个疑问正好证明了
But this doubt just proves
我是圣徒/
that I'm st/l/
今天还活着
alive today
哈哈哈哈
Huh Huh Huh
耶耶耶耶
Yeah Yeah Yeah
是的是的
Yeah Yeah
哈哈哈哈
Huh Huh Huh
耶耶耶耶
Yeah Yeah Yeah
是的是的
Yeah Yeah
我自私吗？我是不是太淘气了？
Am I selfish? Am I being naughty?
我只是不想失去你
I just don't wanna lose you
生意一个接一个，时间很慢/y
Biz' by biz', time is slow/y
耗尽
running out
当你觉得这样的时候，抬起你的下巴
When you feel like this, ho/d your chin up
我们必须继续前进，对吧？
We have to move forward, r/jghz'?
/准备好了
/'m ready
这么一个纯洁疯狂的宝宝
Such a pure and crazy BABY
如此傲慢和听话的BAB Y
Such an arrogant and obedient BAB Y
有点像被禁止的应用程序/e。一切（s。。。
Kinda like the forbidden app/e. Everything (s...
哦是的
OH YEAH
Bo/d拥抱为000/
Bo/d embraces are 000/
伟大的结局是000/
Great endings are 000/
723加油！
7, 2, 723 GO!
爱可以去BAN BAN BA BA BAN
Love can go BAN BAN BA BA BA BAN
带上符文的布鲁姆
and take bloom in a rune
（呼呼）
(Hu Huh)
倾盆大雨可以拥抱
Pouring rains can hug
整个星球都很接近
an entire planet close
哇哇哇（Huh）
WOH WOH WOH (Huh)
让我们g0 BAN BAN BA BA BAN
Letis g0 BAN BAN BA BA BA BAN
培育这个符文，让i2'绽放
to nurture this rune and let i2' bloom
按你的收费
By fee//ng you there
BAN BAN公司
BAN BAN
请不要伪造！
Please don '2' forge!
爱可以去BAN BAN BA BA BAN
Love can go BAN BAN BA BA BA BAN
并在符文中绽放（胡呼）
and take bloom in a rune (Hu Huh)
即使虹膜梦想终有一天会结束
Even if iris a dream that will end one day
“2”无关紧要，
Doesn '2' matter,
我爱你（嗯）
I love you (Huh)
让我们g0 BAN BAN BA BA BAN
Letis g0 BAN BAN BA BA BA BAN
让这个符文在未来绽放
to make this rune bloom in the times to come
直到我们再次见面
Until the day we meet again
班班班班
BAN BAN BA BA BA BAN
符文p/ka/（Huh）
Rune p/ka/ (Huh)
班班班班
BAN BAN BA BA BA BAN
符文p/ka/（Huh）
Rune p/ka/ (Huh)
班班班班
BAN BAN BA BA BA BAN
符文p/ka/（Huh）
Rune p/ka/ (Huh)
花是白色的。
Flowers are white.
它们的气味温和。
Their scent is mild.
太阳很亮。
The sun is shiny.
符文也很闪亮。
Runes are shiny too.
海亚特飞。
Hayate flies.
弗雷亚唱歌。
Freyja sings.
我也唱歌！
I sing too!
呵呵，“我马上就来！”
Hehe, "|'m comin' right atcha!"